<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<post>
		<id>23</id>
		<title>Scuba Divers Discover Priceless Treasure Trove</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

Time is a story keeper , leaving memories and objects as a path for us to revisit. A group of <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Gold.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-28 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Gold-300x197.jpg" alt="Gold" width="300" height="197" /></a>
unsuspecting scuba divers allowed their curiosities to lead them to the largest cache of gold to be discovered on the seafloor of the Mediterranean Harbor of Caesarea, with most being in nearly mint condition.

The group of scuba divers unwittingly noticed the brilliance of what appeared to be a toy coin on the seabed and it was only after further exploring that they quickly realized what they had stumbled upon. The divers excavated the coins and immediately turned them over to the Marine Archaeology Unit of the Israeli Antiques Authority, who have since planned to further unearth the area. The amateur divers displayed great respect for the archaeological find, and have since been deemed model citizens with hearts of gold. This is the largest discovery of gold in Israel, with 2,000 coins uncovered of various denominations with the oldest being a quarter dinar minted in Palermo, Sicily.

There are many theories as to the origin of these coins, and how they seemed to surface after over 1,000 years. Kobi Sharvit, director of Marine Archaeology Unit of the antiques authority theorizes <strong><i>“</i><i>There is probably a shipwreck there of an official treasury boat which was on its way to the central government in Egypt with taxes that had been collected”</i></strong>.  The coins likely surfaced due to storms and natural erosion, luckily this record breaking discovery was not swept to sea. Skilled numismatist Robert Cole had the pleasure of examining the coins and proclaims<strong><i> “</i><i>The coins are in an excellent state of preservation, and despite the fact they were at the bottom of the sea for about a thousand years, they did not require any cleaning or conservation intervention from the metallurgical laboratory.” </i></strong>The coins are said to be priceless in both their numerical and historical value.

Bullion Buddies, what would you do if you unwittingly discovered a gleaming treasure trove of GOLD?

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/goldcoins.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-30" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/goldcoins-300x200.jpg" alt="goldcoins" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/coins2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-32" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/coins2-300x201.jpg" alt="coins2" width="300" height="201" /></a>

<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xeA5_Ejl9J0?rel=0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Gold-300x1971.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/f124cb93-04eb-41b7-96a3-50e5fdf3cec5wallpaper1.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/coins2.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/0.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/goldcoins.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Gold.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|||||</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>scuba-divers-discover-priceless-treasure-trove</slug>
		<Date>20150220</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>67</id>
		<title>3 Most Frequently Asked Questions About Precious Metals</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/123.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-50 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/123-300x225.jpg" alt="123" width="300" height="225" /></a>The United States has been making money since 1972, the first form of money being coins! These early coins were composed of precious metals and had actual value which led many individuals to begin collecting them. But does that mean everyone should just suddenly
jump into gold and silver? No, it does not. Precious metals are not for everyone. Just like any other investing, it is absolutely crucial that you obtain substantial knowledge of the products, as well as, the highlights and pitfalls prior to beginning a collection. So, let's get you started!

<strong>The 3 Most Frequently Asked Questions About Precious Metals:</strong>

<strong>What is U.S. 90 % silver coin and why is it highly recommended? </strong>

90% silver coins include quarters, dimes, and half-dollars minted before 1965. A face value dollar is how 90% silver coins are sold, meaning despite its composition 4 quarters for example minted before 1965 would equal $1 face value. A face value dollar is either 10 dimes, four quarters, or two half-dollars. A face value dollar contains .715 ounces of silver. 90% silver coins are highly recommended simply because it is often the cheapest, most divisible, most widely recognized and traded form or silver.

<strong>What is a round?</strong>

Silver rounds are composed of one troy ounce of .999 fine silver, the 99.9% pure silver coins are produced by various private refineries and are not just round "blanks" of silver. Silver rounds are made with varying designs, at times depicting highly trade-able coins. Regardless of the picture on their front and back, silver rounds do not have monetary value.

<strong>What is a Key Date Coin ? </strong>

In coin collecting, a key date refers to a date (or date and mint mark combination) of a given coin series or set that is harder to obtain than other dates in the series. This is because low mintage coins were frequently kept by collectors and saw little or no circulation, while common dates were rarely saved and typically became heavily worn. The next level of difficult to obtain coins in a series are often referred to as semi-key dates or simply semi-keys. Often times key date coins will be certified by top grading companies, including but not limited to NGC &amp; PCGS.

<strong>Bullion Fun Facts:</strong>
<ul>
 	<li>Several women have appeared on U.S. coins. The very first woman was actually not an American, she was a Spanish Queens. Featured on a commemorative coin, Queens Isabella of Spain was the first lady to be case on a W.S. coin in 1893.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
 	<li>1964 was the last year the United States Minted quarters with 90% silver.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
 	<li>In 1964 you could purchase a gallon of gas for 25 cents, today that same silver quarter is worth about $3.00!</li>
</ul>
<ul>
 	<li>A 1964 silver quarter will still buy you a gallon of gas for your car! But, a 1965 quarter well that will only get you a shiny GUMBALL!</li>
</ul>
<em><strong>We have some pre 1964 quarters, do you?</strong></em>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/123-300x225.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/123.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>knowledge-is-power-purchase-power</slug>
		<Date>20150422</Date>
		<category>Precious Metals Investing</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>92</id>
		<title><![CDATA[New & Improved Bullion Exchanges]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

Welcome to the newly improved BullionExchanges.com! We are thrilled to announce our <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/new-and-improved-site-banner.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-17 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/new-and-improved-site-banner-300x168.jpg" alt="new and improved site banner" width="300" height="168" /></a>website re-launch, which was designed to create a user friendly experience for both desktop and mobile users. Our revamped website includes features like responsive design, faster loading pages, interactive charts, one step checkout, and a plethora of other useful features. We invite you to take moment to navigate the new website, but first please see the overhaul details below where you'll find a wealth of information.

<strong>Improved Searches</strong>

Do you know exactly which product you’re interested in? Our newly improved advanced search functions located on the top-right of the screen allow for seamless searches. This feature has been designed to assist in product searches, auto filling and suggesting products you may have been looking for with a drop down to fine tune your search.

<strong>Improved Navigation</strong>

Effortlessly browse links that are organized to help you find the products you are interested in quickly and efficiently. You'll also find that all pages load significantly faster!

<strong>Mobile Friendly</strong>

Explore our new and improved website on your tablet or smartphone, where you can navigate and purchase products! This feature allows customers to stay in the loop of constantly changing precious metals prices and gives them the opportunity to makes purchases from any device.

<strong>Live Spot Prices</strong>

Track the market with our new spot price charts located on the top and right on the right side of the home page.  Analyze current prices at a glance or hover over the chart to find the price by minute. Click on the chart or the tabs at the top of the page to view spot price charts and historical market developments for God, Silver, Platinum, and Palladium.  Stay informed with market news updated frequently to reflect significant occurrences in the market, this feature can be found on the bottom of our webpage under company info.

<strong>Our Blog</strong>

While you are waiting for the next big news in precious metals, consider Bullion Exchanges as your go to for the most current news on precious metals. A subject as vast as precious metals presents little difficulty in selecting the most informative topics to present to our visitors and we are excited to provide of variety of useful information to our visitors. Our blog can be found on the top and on the right side of the home page above the live spot price chart.

<strong>Learning Center</strong>

<em>Questions or Concerns? </em> Navigate the learning center to explore your precious metals curiosities and potential concerns with becoming a collector/investor.

We are elated to share this improved shopping experienced with our customers!  You may notice additional features such as one step check out, if you have any questions about the new features,

or notice a problem, please feel free to contact us at customerservice@bullionexchanges.com, or by phone at 212-354-1517. We appreciate your business and look forward to hearing from you!]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/new-and-improved-site-banner-300x168.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text></image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>new-improved-bullion-exchanges</slug>
		<Date>20150422</Date>
		<category>Miscellaneous</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>102</id>
		<title>The Story of Philadelphia Coin Dealer Israel Switt</title>
		<content><![CDATA[Augustus Saint-Gauden is revered as one the most influential artists of his time, he was one the  first chosen in 1904 for membership to the American Academy of Arts and Letters,  and was elected a member of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences in 1896.

Saint-Gauden referred to his early relief portraits as "medallions" and took a great interest in the art of the coin.  Chosen by President Roosevelt to redesign the coinage at the beginning of the 20th century, he designed the double eagle coin which features a flying eagle on the reverse side and Augustus Saint-Gaudens' depiction of Lady Liberty on the obverse side. It was adapted for minting several times, but is still considered one of the most beautiful American coins ever issued.

Although 445,500 specimens of the Saint-Gaudens double eagle were minted in 1933, none were ever officially circulated because President Franklin Roosevelt decided to abandon the gold standard.  All of the coins were melted down, with the exception of 10 which disappeared from the Philadelphia Mint.

The family of Philadelphia coin dealer Israel Switt was granted the rights to 10 rare gold coins after a long battle which commenced when Switt's daughter gave the coins to the Philadelphia Mint to be inspected only to have the coins seized by the government.  In response to the seizure the Switt family filed a lawsuit against the government in 2011, claiming that it had previously split the proceeds with another owner in 2002 setting a precedent. They lost the lawsuit, however the U.S. appeals court overturned the verdict on Friday, April 17, 2015.

The U.S. Department of Treasury argued that the eagles were stolen from the U.S. Mint , and made claims that Switt was investigated in the 1930's , however their claims were quickly  invalidated with opposing attorney claiming he may have traded scrap gold for them. Since the verdict overturn they have not released any comments.

The family attorney Barry Berke said: “Congress clearly intended for there to be limits on the government's ability to seek forfeiture of citizens' property, and today's ruling reaffirms that those limits are real and won't be excused when the government violates them".

Keep your coins, the story they tell may make history some day!

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Saint_Gaudens-300x1531.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text></image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>the-story-of-philadelphia-coin-dealer-israel-switt</slug>
		<Date>20150428</Date>
		<category>Precious Metals Investing</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>107</id>
		<title>Where To Store Your Bullion</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

The term portfolio refers to any collection of financial assets such as bullion. <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/vault.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-108 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/vault-300x237.jpg" alt="vault" width="300" height="237" /></a>Portfolios may be held by individual investors and/or managed by financial professionals, hedge funds, banks and other financial institutions. In terms of storing your Bullion properly there are three options which will ensure the protection of your collection/investment. Each presents different advantages and disadvantages, which is why it is imperative to consider each option and decide which if not all will be beneficial to your needs.

<strong>Common Practices in Storing Your Bullion Properly</strong>

<strong><u>At Home </u></strong>

Storing your bullion at your home ensures constant accessibility and control over your valuables, however it is crucial to keep your bars and coins in secure fireproof area in the event of a fire or natural disaster. It is also wise to store your Bullion in a location that is not accessible to others, which will provide additional security against theft. If you choose to store your Bullion at your home, consider increasing your insurance. This option not only allows you to dictate where and how your bullion is stored, it also eliminates the fees and policies of third party providers.

<strong><u>In a Safe Deposit Box</u></strong>

This method for storing your Bullion certainly ensures security, and is an affordable option. The disadvantage is that your access is limited to the financial institutions hours of operation, and there are fees which are subject to change.  Prior to choosing this option, you must confirm the insurance policy provided for your bullion in the event of natural disaster or fire.

<strong><u>In a Depository</u></strong>

Another option for storing your Bullion is a depository, it is the most secure option. Depositories will fully ensure your Bullion, in addition to offering services in the event you need access to your valuables outside of their business hours. Though this option can be costly, if chosen it is vital to store your valuables separate and not in a pool to further protect your Bullion against unexpected closures and natural disasters.

There are alternatives, however avoid non-secure locations such as self-storage facilities. Safeguard the value of your wealth by securing your valuables in a dry, cool, fireproof, and most importantly discrete location.

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/vault-300x237.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/vault.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>where-to-store-your-bullion</slug>
		<Date>20150501</Date>
		<category>Precious Metals Investing</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>111</id>
		<title>Bullion Exchanges New 2015 1 oz Canadian Maple E=mc2 Privy</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

Bullion Exchanges and the world class refinery Royal Canadian Mint are pleased to release<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/emc21.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-113 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/emc21-300x300.jpg" alt="e=mc2" width="300" height="300" /></a> the 2015 1 oz. Canadian Maple <strong>E=mc2</strong> Privy Reverse Proof Silver Coin commemorating <strong>Albert Einstein’s </strong>100 year anniversary of the General Theory of Relativity today. The Royal Canadian Mint produced this custom design with a limited mintage of only 50,000 coins. These coins are in brand new, mint condition, and since they are a Bullion Exchanges exclusive the only place you can purchase them worldwide is with us!

This coin is a must have for Special Theory of RELATIVITY FANS! Physicists, astronomers, historians; anyone with a passion for science and Einstein’s genius will cherish this original and upscale keepsake. The 2015 1 oz. Canadian Maple <strong>E=mc2</strong> Privy Reverse Proof Silver Coin is the first release in a series which is currently in the production phase.

The reverse design features the bullion coin’s Silver Maple Leaf in a reverse proof finish; the privy mark commemorates the Special Theory of Relativity with the groundbreaking formula <strong>E=mc2. </strong>The obverse features a right facing effigy of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II by Susana Blunt.

The 2015 1 oz. Canadian Maple <strong>E=mc2</strong> Privy Reverse Proof Silver Coin featuring a brand new design, with a unique reverse proof finish which is rare in coins produced by the Royal Canadian Mint is composed of 1 troy ounce of  .9999 fine silver and bares a $5 denomination.

These 2015 1 oz. Canadian Maple <strong>E=mc2</strong> Privy Reverse Proof Silver Coins are being struck at the Royal Canadian Mint in reverse proof finish. <strong>The mintage of these coins will be strictly limited to only 50, 000 coins making them highly collectible and sure to be sought out. </strong>

Single coins will be packaged in protective plastic coin flips. Multiples of 25 will be packaged in the original Royal Canadian Mint tube. Orders of 500 coins or more will be packaged in “Monster Boxes”. Bullion Exchanges offers free shipping on all domestic orders, which will be accepted both by phone and online. All prices are quoted in US dollars are determined based on the current spot price.

It was in 1915 when Einstein completed his masterpiece, the General Theory of Relativity – cutting-edge ideas on gravity and the motion of large scale objects like stars, plants, and galaxies. An earlier form of Einstein’s iconic formula had been unveiled ten years prior as part of his Special Theory of Relativity (1905). It described what happens when objects reach the speed of light – a concept that must have seemed pure science fiction 110 years ago.

This unique coin is attractive to both the first-time precious metal buyer and the long-term investor.

Bullion Exchanges President Eric Gozenput states…

“We are especially pleased to have had the opportunity to collaborate with the Royal Canadian Mint, a world renowned refinery and look forward to many projects in the future.” “The Royal Canadian Mint’s exceptional attention to detail, and innovative refining practices have made this process nothing short of thrilling!”

Located in the heart of New York City’s Diamond District, Bullion Exchanges is a trusted Precious Metals Retailer. Bullion Exchanges offers a vast retail selection of products including but not limited to, metals that range from the ever popular gold and silver to the newly emerging platinum and palladium.

&nbsp;

<img src="http://bullionexchanges.com/media/wysiwyg/einsteininfographic.png" alt="" width="700" height="2000" />]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/emc21.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/emc2.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>bullion-exchanges-new-2015-1-oz-canadian-maple-emc2-privy</slug>
		<Date>20150506</Date>
		<category>New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>150</id>
		<title>Graded vs Ungraded , Which Do You Prefer?</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/graded-vs-undgraded-00000005.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-172" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/graded-vs-undgraded-00000005.jpg" alt="graded vs undgraded (00000005)" width="850" height="500" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you own a coin that you genuinely believe is of substantial value, then it is worth taking
the time and money to have it certified, especially if you are interested in selling it in the future and want to realise its full potential.</p>
In the past, coin grading was a vague process and coins were categorized as good, fine, or uncirculated. As time went on, it became evident that a clearly defined and internationally accepted grading system needed to be established.

Coin grading has evolved over the years to a system of finer grade distinctions. Today, a coin is graded and given its market value based on its appearance and overall condition, there are five critical components that help determine this.
<ol>
 	<li>The Surface Preservation: This refers to the number of marks and scratches on the surface and the severity of these, in addition to the overall condition of the coin.</li>
 	<li>Strike: This is the process of imprinting a design onto a blank coin, more specifically the strength of the imprint.</li>
 	<li>Coloration: This can be described as a gage in how much the coin has changed from its original color. Discoloration may be due to age, improper cleaning, storage, or handling of the coin.</li>
 	<li>Luster: This refers to the appearance of a coin’s surface. It can be described as either satiny, proof like, or frosty. When you grade the luster of a coin, you basically grade the intensity, beauty, and integrity of the coin’s ability to reflect light, within the luster characteristics of that issue.</li>
 	<li>Eye appeal: This incorporates all of the above elements</li>
</ol>
Rarity is a significant factor in coin grading and in determining a coins value, there are several scales which have been developed for the definition of the rarity of a particular coin with the most common being “Sheldon Rarity Scale” and the “Universal Rarity Scale”.

When a coin is graded it is given a numerical value between 1 and 70. A PO-1 represents a barely identifiable coin and a MS/PR-70 represents a perfect coin with a full strike and no markings (these are incredibly rare). PO stands for basal (poor) state and MS stands for mint state. Between these opposite grades, in ascending order you get:
<ul>
 	<li>Fair (Fair): This is where you can identify the type of coin, although it might be bent or have holes.</li>
 	<li>Almost Good (AG): The design is outlined, parts of the legend are worn and smooth and the date is difficult to make out</li>
 	<li>Good (G): These are coins which are quite worn but have a distinguishable date. Design, legends and date are clear, but not sharp.</li>
 	<li>Very Good (VG): A coin showing extensive wear but for which the date and most lettering are still legible and devices are visible. (Devices can be defined as a design that is found on any coin. It is usually the bust of an individual who is a country symbol at a specific point in history. It might also be a country’s insignia.)</li>
 	<li>Fine (F): Moderate to heavy wear, entire design, legend and date are clear and bold, but it might still lack details</li>
 	<li>Very Fine (VF): Light to medium wear, the coins are slightly worn on the edges but sharp in details and an almost mint luster still evident.</li>
 	<li>Extremely Fine (XF or EF): used to describe coins which have been slightly circulated with light wear only on the highest points.</li>
 	<li>Almost Uncirculated (AU) Very small trace of wear only on the highest points. Very hard to tell the different between an AU and an Unc. Coins.</li>
</ul>
A grading finalizer assigns the final grade of the coin and thereafter the coin is sonically sealed in a protective, inert plastic holder known as a “slab”. This third-party appraisal of a coin’s physical condition, back by a guarantee, and a national network of reputable coin dealers provided an extremely reliable form of protection for rare coin consumers who could then participate in the coin market with greater confidence.

It’s imperative that you choose a reputable coin grading service to evaluate your coins and presently the NGC (Numismatic Guaranty Corporation) and PCGS (Professional Coin Grading Service) form the top tier of a three tier grading service. They are the two most reliable and consistent services and use a consensus method of grading.  A <a href="https://bullionexchanges.com/how-to/ngc-pcgs-graded-coins">NGC or PCGS coin grading</a> and approval have a higher demand in the market.

Although ungraded coins are undoubtedly cheaper and do not take on expenses beyond its cost, they are a hugely risky investment and as is pointed out, the true value of a coin lies in having it graded correctly, by an established and knowledgeable coin grading service.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/graded-vs-undgraded-00000005.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/graded-vs-undgraded-00000003.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/graded-vs-undgraded-00000002.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>||</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>graded-vs-ungraded-which-do-you-prefer</slug>
		<Date>20150626</Date>
		<category>Precious Metals Investing</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>164</id>
		<title>China To Adopt Gold Standard</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/download.png"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-166" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/download-300x296.png" alt="download" width="300" height="296" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">The gold standard arose from a widespread acceptance of gold as currency thousands of years ago, and in less than a weeks’ time China will receive approval from its Central Bank to back the Yuan in Gold. Ken Hoffman of Bloomberg Intelligence says this would be a “game changer”, and does not believe the change will be the catalyst to severe constraint for the Chinese Central Bank. He explains in further detail that their decision to move toward the gold standard will help attract foreign capital. Historically moving toward the gold standard enabled the United States to become an International Monetary Fund after World War II. The U.S. held most of the world’s gold, and therefore many countries simply pegged the value of their currency to the dollar, thus making the dollar the defacto world currency. Hoffman states that if they receive approval China’s decision to adopt the Gold Standard will cause the rest of the world to view the metal as currency again.</p>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/download-300x2961.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/download.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/a-view-of-the-peoples-bank-of-china-the-countrys-central-bank-located-in-beijing.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>||</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>china-to-adopt-gold-standard</slug>
		<Date>20150626</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>180</id>
		<title>Greece Closes All Financial Institutions, Creating a Gold Rush!</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

Greece has closed Banks, and stopped selling gold coins to the public after enforcing capital control. On June 27, 2015, the Greek government announced a shutdown of all
<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/euro-373008_640.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-181 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/euro-373008_640-300x239.jpg" alt="euro-373008_640" width="300" height="239" /></a>banks in the country for at least ten days, stating they would re-open on July 6<sup>th</sup>. Gold rose on Monday amid the crisis but has since eased down.

Once re-opened withdrawals would be limited to 60 euros a day for each account with exemptions made for pension payments. The Athens stock exchange was also to be closed for a week, leaving both the people and investors in a state of unrest with a strong desire to move away from the euro.

This drastic decision has left investors searching for refuge, with the common view being that this was triggered by the turmoil of the Great recession. The demand for gold has risen fundamentally with gold futures climbing steadily.

GoldCore Ltd. has reported three times the average sales since the closing of banks and financial institutions in Greece. Bullion Vault a highly reputable internet peer-to-peer gold and silver bullion exchange with headquarters in the United Kingdom reported a jump in sales which is an indication of more extensive increments. Director of Frankfurt-based CoinInvest.com, states “When people learned that Greek banks will be closed, they started to think that it may not be a bad idea to have some money in gold.”

European nations are acting quickly, thus far for 2015 21.786 million ounces of silver American Eagles have been sold, 266,000 ounces of gold American Eagles have been purchased, while 95,000 gold American Buffalos have been purchased.

The impact is evident, but yields the opportunity for long term investments.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/euro-373008_640-300x2391.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/141229_Open_Europe_Blog.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/euro-373008_640.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>||</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>greece-closes-all-financial-institutions-creating-a-gold-rush</slug>
		<Date>20150702</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>188</id>
		<title>U.S. Mint SOLD OUT of Silver Eagles</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-1-oz-silver-american-eagle-1-coin-mint-sealed-monster-box-500-coins-726.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-189 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-1-oz-silver-american-eagle-1-coin-mint-sealed-monster-box-500-coins-726-300x300.jpg" alt="2015-1-oz-silver-american-eagle-1-coin-mint-sealed-monster-box-500-coins-726" width="300" height="300" /></a>Due to noteworthy increase in demand, the United States Mints inventory of American Silver Eagle Coins has been exhausted. Though temporary, the Mint estimates it will be a month before they are able to replenish supplier’s inventories.

This is the second time in nine months that the mint has been sold out of the American Eagle Silver Coins, with the first occurrence in November 2014. Amidst the extreme decline in the price of silver, insightful investors and distributors have snatched up as much of this popular item as possible.

The Silver American Eagle Coin continues to be coveted by investors and collectors alike, because of its more prominent affordability.

Thankfully, Bullion Exchanges remains your direct source for these highly sought after Silver American Eagles. These coins are becoming seemingly impossible to obtain, so if you are interested in buying or selling  <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/catalogsearch/result/?cat=0&amp;q=2015+silver++american+eagle">American Silver Eagles </a>browse our website today or give us a call at 800.852.6884.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-1-oz-silver-american-eagle-1-coin-mint-sealed-monster-box-500-coins-726-300x3001.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/eagles.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/2015-1-oz-silver-american-eagle-1-coin-mint-sealed-monster-box-500-coins-726.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>||</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>u-s-mint-sold-out-of-silver-eagles</slug>
		<Date>20150710</Date>
		<category>New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>198</id>
		<title>Platinum under $1,000/oz for first time since February 2009</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

Platinum fell underneath the $1,000 an ounce check on Friday, leaving costs in triple-figure region surprisingly since February 2009, as financial specialists kept on losing confidence in its principal interest viewpoint.

Vulnerability over the precious metals even with a rising dollar — set for its greatest week by week pick up in two months — is likewise weighing on costs, with gold hitting eight-month lows and palladium at its most minimal since late 2012.

Spot platinum fell to a low of $998.50/oz, down 0.7% at 10:41am GMT.

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/palladium-maple-platinum-eagle-coins.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-206 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/palladium-maple-platinum-eagle-coins-300x214.jpg" alt="palladium-maple-platinum-eagle-coins" width="300" height="214" /></a>Yield from South African platinum makers has been rising this year subsequent to disabling strike activity in 2014. Top player Anglo American Platinum reported a 60% ascent in refined equal generation in the second quarter.

Chinese jewelry utilization has been soft this year, while evidences of a stoppage in the worldwide auto industry, which utilizes the metal as a part of exhaust systems, is likewise undermining feeling towards platinum, examiners said.

"A major problem is that investors have lost faith in the long-term story and the reason is probably the diesel issue," Macquarie associate director Matthew Turner said.”

Information proposes general request in number-one customer China has additionally been soft this year. Mitsubishi examiner Jonathan Steward said platinum turnover on the Shanghai Gold Trade was down 21% in the first half.

"With jewelry buying suffering as a result of the equity market crash and economic slowdown, there is possibly more speculative activity than normal, helped by a rotation out of equities and into hard assets," he said in an interview with the Reuters Global Gold Forum this week.

"Overall, we are somewhat negative on jewelry fabrication demand this year, and cautious on industrial buying."

Platinum has not been underneath $1,000 since mid-2009, after the breakdown of Lehman Brothers and begin of the worldwide budgetary emergency started wide based offering of hard resources and frenzy over the standpoint for mechanical metals request.

This year it has been undermined by the way that last year's uncommon five-month strike among platinum excavators in SA — the wellspring of seventy five percent of worldwide platinum supply — neglected to lift costs, recommending shoppers were abundantly supplied.

Platinum's generally abnormal markdown to gold has come to its most astounding subsequent to late 2012, at almost $145/oz.

That has driven investors to venture over from the business. Gross short positions in NYMEX platinum positions sat at 93% of the record high a week ago, UBS said in a note, while platinum-supported trade exchanged trusts (ETFs) have seen surges this week.

Platinum ETFs, which issue securities sponsored by physical metal, saw enormous inflows
in 2013 and 2014 after the dispatch of a rand-named item in SA. While those stores have not been intensely sold, inflows have tailed off this year.

Based in New York City, Bullion Exchanges remains your direct source for premium  <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/platinum-palladium.html">platinum coins and bars</a>.

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/palladium-maple-platinum-eagle-coins-300x2141.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/palladium-maple-platinum-eagle-coins.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/scrap_platinum_bars.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>||</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>platinum-under-1000oz-for-first-time-since-february-2009</slug>
		<Date>20150717</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>221</id>
		<title><![CDATA[Johnson Matthey sold Gold & Silver Refining Business to Asahi]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/march-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-212" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/march-1.jpg" alt="march-1" width="960" height="404" /></a>

Johnson Matthey, a worldwide pioneer in sustainable technologies, sold its Gold and Silver Refining business to Asahi Holdings, Inc. This finishes the exchange which was initially declared on fifteenth December 2014.

Remarking on the exchange, Robert MacLeod, Chief Executive of Johnson Matthey said: "The divestment of the Gold and Silver Refining business is in line with our long term strategy to focus on areas where we can use our expertise in chemistry and its applications to deliver high technology solutions or that provide a strategic service to the wider Johnson Matthey group."

In spite of the fact that Johnson Matthey will never again be delivering their bars and most merchants are sold out, Bullion Exchanges is your immediate manufacturer direct source for these exceedingly sought after <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/catalogsearch/result/?cat=0&amp;q=johnson+matthey">silver bars</a>.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url></image_url>
		<image_alt_text></image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>johnson-matthey-sold-gold-silver-refining-business-to-asahi</slug>
		<Date>20150717</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>233</id>
		<title>Gold ricochets back above $1,100/oz from five-year low</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold.jpg"><img class=" size-full wp-image-234 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold.jpg" alt="gold" width="640" height="360" /></a>Gold rebounded and is above $1,100 an ounce as of last Thursday from the past session’s
five year low, as a retreat in the dollar incited financial specialists to exploit the value drop to buy back into the market.

Numerous investors remained distrustful towards the precious metal, be that as it may, after its most profound one-day misfortune in about two years last Monday, pushing costs through the chart levels and setting it up for further shortcoming.

Gold has been undermined for this present year by assumptions that the U.S. Federal
Reserve is on track to raise premium rates without precedent for about 10 years, boosting the expense of holding non-yielding bullion and lifting the dollar.

AvaTrade’s chief markey analyst, Naeem Aslam states:

<em>"Gold is falling out of favour as the Fed is preparing to increase borrowing costs,"</em>

<em>"This will remain the major hurdle for any upside move for the precious metal and traders will likely be selling into these rallies.</em>

<em>"The bounce in gold is nothing but a technical trade, as most major momentum indicators are showing that the recent sell-off is overdone."</em>

Gold’s recession last Monday was exacerbated by huge exchanging volumes on the Shanghai Gold Trade after speculators dumped more than $500,000,000 of bullion in seconds amidst early Asian trading hours.

Specialized examiners, who think about past value examples to gage the future heading of the trading, say the following focus for gold underneath last Wednesdays low close to $1,087/oz is $1,044, its 2010 low.

Possessions in the greatest gold-backed exchange traded fund, SPDR Gold Shares, shrank for a fifth day last Wednesday to their most minimal since 2008.

Some interest developed for physical metal, on the other hand a retreat in the dollar, which fell 0.5% against a currency basket, supported some purchasing in China overnight, merchants said.

MKS states:

<em>“The on-shore premium in Shanghai continued to trade in positive territory, sitting around $1.50 for the majority of the day, supporting an initial test of $1,100.” </em>

The gold debacle last week has prodded a purchasing spree of bullion coin in the United States, as government information demonstrated deals during the current month have hit their most elevated in over two years.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text></image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>gold-ricochets-back-above-1100oz-from-five-year-low</slug>
		<Date>20150727</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>236</id>
		<title>Gold barely changed ahead of Fed declaration</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-stones.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-237 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-stones-300x200.jpg" alt="gold-stones" width="300" height="200" /></a>Gold floated close to its weakest level following mid 2010 on Tuesday, reflecting spectacular delay to offer up bullion in the midst of the developing desire of a close term climb in U.S. interest rates.

The Federal Reserve starts a two-day meeting later in the day where policy makers are liable to flag that a rate trek later in the year is sure as the U.S. economy fortifies.

A further descend in Chinese equities after their most profound defeat subsequent to 2007
on Monday has scarcely influenced trading in gold, normally seen as refuge metal.

ANZ Bank commodity strategist Victor Thianpiriya stated in Singapore, “If anything it’s a little bit surprising that we haven’t had the safe-haven bid in gold even though you’ve had these big risk-off moves in the Chinese equity market”.

Spot gold was flat at $1,094.40/oz by 2:50am GMT.

Bullion tumbled to as low as 41,077 on Friday, it’s least expensive since February 2010, extending its losing rushed to a fifth week.

The prior defeat in Chinese stock in July in addition to the Greek debt crisis neglected to start any place of refuge offer for gold, with financial specialists to a great extent concentrated on an approaching U.S. rate climb. That has reinforced the dollar and diminished the request of non-interest bearing resources, for example, bullion.

Financial specialist trust in gold stayed flimsy after last week’s slide joined by enormous trading volumes in New York and Shanghai. The metal lost more than 3% last week, the most since Spring.

HSBC, which has sliced its gold value conjectures during the current year and next, said the valuable metal was liable to stay underweight in the fleeting and "could move to within striking distance of $1,000/oz before recovering".

The enormous driver for most cost misfortunes for gold is an approaching U.S. rate increment and analysts are anticipating more affirmation from the Fed towards that end when the current week’s policy meetings are set to conclude on Wednesday.

“We’re still expecting a fourth-quarter lift off in the Fed funds rate and that’s when you’ll see the trough in gold or we could potentially see gold take another leg lower” said Mr.Thianpiriya, pegging the following significant back at $1,045 if $1,080 is broken once more.

U.S. gold for August delivery slipped 0.2% to $1,094.10/oz.

Likewise weighing on the assessment, China’s net gold imports from primary channel Hong Kong tumbled to a 10-month low in June, reflecting feeble interest from the major devouring nation.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-stones-300x2001.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-stones.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>gold-barely-changed-ahead-of-fed-declaration</slug>
		<Date>20150728</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>241</id>
		<title>Gold stabilizes as investors look for signals on U.S. rate trek timing</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-21.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-242" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-21.jpg" alt="gold-21" width="800" height="305" /></a>

Gold steadied on Wednesday as the dollar mollified, yet was still trading near an almost
five-and-a-half-year low hit a week ago as analysts and investors anticipated the result of a Federal Reserve meeting for signs on the timing of the first U.S. rate ascend in about 10 years.

Policymakers are prone to assert that only steady indications of a  solid U.S. economy and labor market would put them on track to bring interest rates up in advancing months, analysts said.

For non-interest yielding gold, higher interest rates mean costs could feel obligated.

Robin Bhar, Societe Generale analyst says “We bounced from the low but we are little changed and waiting for the Fed’s statement tonight and the second-quarter gross domestic product tomorrow”.

“These are two events that should set direction for the next few weeks although the market is expecting no change in the Fed’s language.”

The metal reached $1,077 a week ago, it’s weakest since February 2010, after a sell-off on trades in New York and Shanghai, when analysts and investors cut their vulnerability on apprehensions of further value decays.

In the wake of breaking the $1,100 bolster level, gold has found it difficult to recoup and keep afloat showing bearish financial specialists kept on hovering in the market.

The dollar declined yesterday and was at 0.2% against a basket dominant currencies ahead of the policy statement due this evening.

Commerzbank states “If a rate hike in September were to be signaled, this would doubtless drive up the U.S. dollar, which would ultimately weigh on the gold price, for the Fed Fund Features have so far only priced in roughly 40% of a rate hike in September”.

European equities progressed, impelled by additions in the U.S. and Asian markets on trusts that Beijing could stem the defeat in its markets without harm to the world’s second greatest economy.

Worldwide gold interest shrank to its most minimal since 2009 in the second quarter as China emptied trusts into its now pained equities market, as per a report by GFMS, a division of Thomson Reuters.

Possessions of the biggest gold-backed exchange-traded-fund, New York’s SPDR Gold Trust, were unaltered at 21.87 million ounces on Monday, the least since September 2008, after a seven-day slide.

Spot platinum increased 0.6% to $622.75/oz and platinum advanced 0.1% to $982.50/oz, both not a long way above multi-year lows while silver remained unaltered.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-211.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/unnamed-file.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/gold-21.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>||</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>gold-stabilizes-as-investors-look-for-signals-on-u-s-rate-trek-timing</slug>
		<Date>20150729</Date>
		<category>Market News|Precious Metals Investing</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>246</id>
		<title>Greek stocks bashed at reopen, while Chinese commodities burdens continue</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/mount-lycabettus-bell-tower.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-247 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/mount-lycabettus-bell-tower-200x300.jpg" alt="mount-lycabettus-bell-tower" width="200" height="300" /></a>The Greek stock market plummeted when it reopened on Monday subsequent to being closed down for five weeks, while feeble information from China helped push oil costs to their most reduced in six months and Asian stocks close at their 2015 lows.

Analysis revealed China’s factory activity shrunk by the most in two years, guaranteeing a three-month sell-off in commodity and developing markets would proceed.

Brent oil tumbled to $51 a barrel, it’s most reduced subsequent to the end of January. Industrial metal copper fell to its weakest in six years. Gold was at $1,093 an ounce after its most exceedingly awful month in two years.

Europe was also unstable. Stocks in Athens dove 23% when the market reopened in the wake of shutting down in late June.

Lower-evaluated government bonds additionally saw some minor selling.

That offset strong economic information. Eurozone processing plant action became quicker than beforehand suspected in July.

The Netherlands, Spain, and Italy all reported sound development — Italy’s extension was its best in over four years.

Chris Williamson, chief economist at survey complier Markit says “Policymakers will be reassured by the robust growth rates seen in these countries and the resilience of the manufacturing sector as a whole”.

“Especially as growth is likely to pick up again now that Greece has jumped its latest hurdle in the ongoing debt crisis.”

Energetic results from HSBC, Commerzbank, and Heineken likewise helped balance Greece’s inconveniences.

Pickups in Frankfurt and Paris made up for a 0.2% plunge by London’s FTSE.

<strong>Extraordinary fall of China </strong>

China’s poor information kept Asian markets from demonstrating the same flexibility.

MSCI’s broadest record of Asia-Pacific shares outside Japan fell more than 1% to take it near to right on time July’s least level of the year.

Shanghai shares shed 1.9%, Japan’s Nikkei slid 0.3% and South Korea Kospi dropped 1%. Australian stocks dropped 0.4%.

Barclays strategists wrote in an everyday note to customers, “We believe the macroenviroment remains challenging for emerging market assets amid headwinds of low commodity prices, concerns over China and a looming US Federal Reserve tightening cycle”.

New flows data affirmed that pattern. Net remote offering from developing Asia has come to about $10 billion in the course of recent months. Just India has seen lesser inflows.

Recent streams information affirmed that pattern. Net remote offering from developing Asia has come to about $10bn in the course of recent months. Just India has seen minor inflows.

Among the fundamental worldwide currencies, the dollar held relentless in the wake of sliding on Friday on disillusioning US wage development information, at ¥124.14 and $1.0970 to the euro.

Late US financial information has undermined the dollar, yet the more extensive pattern has been to the upside, after the US Federal Reserve invited a rate increment in September during last week’s negotiations.

The US dollar has increased 7.75% so far this year against the world's primary trading currencies, following a 12% ascent a year ago.

As indicated by examination from the BlackRock Investment Institute “the dollar’s recent rally may just be getting started,”

Russ Koesterich of BlackRock says “Since the 1970’s when the Bretton Woods fixed-currency regime ended and currencies began floating, a typical dollar rally has lasted roughly six to seven years”.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/mount-lycabettus-bell-tower-200x3001.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/mount-lycabettus-bell-tower.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>greek-stocks-bashed-at-reopen-while-chinese-commodities-burdens-continue</slug>
		<Date>20150803</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>254</id>
		<title><![CDATA[Bullion Exchanges Releases the 2015 $100 Fine Silver Coin Celebrating Canadian Photographer Yousuf Karsh & Albert Einstein’s Special Theory of Relativity]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/10-oz-silver-albert-einstien-coin-banner-final-page-001.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-256" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/10-oz-silver-albert-einstien-coin-banner-final-page-001-1024x572.jpg" alt="10 oz silver albert einstien coin banner final-page-001" width="604" height="337" /></a>

Bullion Exchanges in collaboration with Manfra, Tordella, &amp; Brooks, and the world class refinery Royal Canadian Mint are pleased to release the 2015 10 oz $100 Silver Coin in celebration of <strong>Albert Einstein’s Special Theory of Relativity</strong> featuring an iconic image of Einstein taken by Canadian photographer Yousuf Karsh. The Royal Canadian Mint produced this custom design with a <strong>limited mintage of only 1,500 coins</strong>. These coins are in brand new, mint condition, and have been produced by the Royal Canadian Mint. Bullion Exchanges is the exclusive distributor of this stunning coin in the United States.

Exchanges President Eric Gozenput states…

“We are particularly enthused by the results of our first collaboration with the Royal Canadian Mint and anticipate Einstein enthusiasts will be ecstatic about the release of this coin. The Royal Canadian mint is widely acclaimed, and we are honored to have worked with and be associated to such an outstanding refinery with knowledge and resources that are simply invaluable. We are excited about our growing partnership, and look forward to potential future collaborations!”

Join the global celebration with this historic <strong>10 oz fine silver coin</strong> commemorating Albert Einstein’s Special Theory of Relativity! 2015 celebrates the 100<sup>th</sup> anniversary of the General Theory of Relativity and the 110<sup>th</sup> anniversary of the Special Theory of Relativity.

This exquisite coin features an original portrait of Albert Einstein taken by Yousuf Karsh in 1948. Karsh is famous for his portraits of Sir Winston Churchill, among other politicians, dignitaries, royalty, and celebrities. The 2015 $100 Albert Einstein Fine Silver coin highlights a unique Canadian connection to Einstein. Canadian photographer Yousuf Karsh (1908-2002) is considered one of the masters of the twentieth century.

Karsh and Einstein were introduced at Princeton’s Institute for Advanced Study in 1948. He took a number of photographs, two of which became the most iconic images of Einstein worldwide. One of them is featured on this coin; it’s down to earth style revealing the humility and humanity behind one of the most powerful minds science has ever known.

Royal Canadian Mint engravers have expertly reproduced the original portrait taken by Yousuf Karsh in 1948. This coin has been exceptionally crafted with exquisite detailing, multiple finishes and a proof field to capture the subtleties of light and form as revealed in Karsh’s original photograph. As a unique addition, Einstein’s breakthrough formula E=mc² has been included within the image.

These 2015 10 oz Albert Einstein Theory of Relativity Silver Coins are being struck at the Royal Canadian Mint. The Royal Canadian Mint produces and markets a family of high purity gold, silver, palladium and platinum Maple Leaf bullion coins. The Mint also provides Canadian and foreign customer with gold and silver processing, including refining, assaying.

Additionally, the Royal Canadian Mint operates a technically advanced and environmentally friendly refinery in which it refines precious metals from a variety of sources including primary producers, industry, recyclers and financial institutions.

<strong>The mintage of these coins will be strictly limited to only 1,500 coins making them highly collectible and sure to be sought out following the success of the 2015 1 oz Silver Canadian Maple Leaf E=mc² Privy Reverse Proof Coin. </strong>

The reverse design features Karsh’s famous portrait of Albert Einstein taken in 1948, with multiple finishes and a proof field within Einstein’s portrait. As a unique addition, Einstein’s breakthrough formula E=mc² has been included within the image. Inscribed on the border are “CANADA”, “100 DOLLARS”, and “2015”. The obverse features a right facing effigy of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II by Susana Blunt with “ELIZABETH II”. And “D.G. REGINA” inscribed near the rim of the coin.

Single coins will arrive from the Royal Canadian Mint in maple presentation cases and beauty boxes. Bullion Exchanges offers free shipping on all domestic orders, which will be accepted both by phone and online. All prices are quoted in US dollars are determined based on the current spot price.

This coin is a must have for<strong> Einstein </strong>fans! Physicists, astronomers, historians; anyone with a passion for science and Einstein’s genius will cherish this original upscale keepsake.

This unique coin is attractive to both the first-time precious metal buyer and the long-term investor.

Located in the heart of New York City’s Diamond District, Bullion Exchanges is a trusted Precious Metals Retailer. Bullion Exchanges offers a vast retail selection of products including but not limited to, metals that range from the ever popular gold and silver to the newly emerging platinum and palladium.

Personality right of Albert Einstein are used with permission of The Hebrew University of Jerusalem. Represented exclusively by Corbis. Official licensed merchandise.

© Estate of Yousuf Karsh]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/10-oz-silver-albert-einstien-coin-banner-final-page-001.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text></image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>bullion-exchanges-releases-the-2015-100-fine-silver-coin-celebrating-canadian-photographer-yousuf-karsh-albert-einsteins-special-theory-of-relativity</slug>
		<Date>20150805</Date>
		<category>New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>269</id>
		<title>Goldman Sachs and HSBC Buy 7.1 Tons of Physical Gold</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/10-countries-hoarding-enormous-stockpiles-of-gold.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-270 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/10-countries-hoarding-enormous-stockpiles-of-gold-300x225.jpg" alt="10-countries-hoarding-enormous-stockpiles-of-gold" width="300" height="225" /></a>On August 6, 2015, Goldman Sachs and HSBC took conveyance of an entirety of 7.1 tons of physical gold. The gold bars were not acquired for bank customers. They were bought for the banks themselves, labelled by the exchange as for shipment to the banks “house” accounts at COMEX.

Goldman Sachs, alone, took 3.2 tons worth of physical gold bars. Yet, even as the firm forms its stockpile, Goldman advises customers not to do so. As per Goldman’s Jeffrey Currie, the long haul viewpoint for gold is disheartening.  According to Currie, <em>“In longer term, we definitely like playing this market on the short side. We think we are in a structural bear market, not only in gold, but across the commodity complex, as the individual commodity stories are reinforcing to one another, creating a negative feedback loop.” </em>

Despite the shenanigans in the paper-gold market, we know the physical business is ablaze. Interest will surpass known supplies by no less than 1,350 tons in 2015. More in 2016. In any case, that won’t prevent somebody from setting up the paper market keeping
in mind the end foal to purchase from the physical market efficiently. This is on the grounds that the baffling gold “supplier last resort” will fill COMEX physical conveyance request, for the minute at any rate, regardless of how high it rises, and regardless of how low different supplies may be.

As indicated by HSBC strategists, there has been a:

<em>“drift towards Fed tightening and the associated USD strength, low global inflationary pressure, weak gold demand from India and China and market positioning and momentum.” </em>

This announcement was made a couple of days before we all found out about the 61% expansion in gold imports to India in the period, April to May. It is impossible that one the greatest players in imports with India did not know this. HSBC officials were positively cunning enough to approve the gigantic buy of physical gold for the bank.

In both cases, the buys are enlisted as being for the advantage of the bank, therefore both investors and collectors alike should follow the lead of the banks in purchasing gold.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/10-countries-hoarding-enormous-stockpiles-of-gold-300x225-1.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/10-countries-hoarding-enormous-stockpiles-of-gold.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>goldman-sachs-and-hsbc-buy-7-1-tons-of-physical-gold</slug>
		<Date>20150820</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>274</id>
		<title>Gold set for its most sizable climb since January as stocks, and the dollar slide</title>
		<content><![CDATA[&nbsp;

Gold stabilized on Friday having hit its most elevated point in over six weeks and was setting out toward its greatest week subsequent to mid-January as further economic data from China has left financial markets shaken.

World stocks plummeted towards their most noticeably bad week of the year, while the dollar index hit its least in almost eight weeks after a Chinese production lines information added to questions about the Federal Reserve raising interest rates one month from now.

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/20140221-gold.png"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-275 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/20140221-gold-300x150.png" alt="20140221-gold" width="300" height="150" /></a>Gold had officially bounced back this week from July’s five-and-a-half-year low, supported by minted of the Federal Reserve’s last strategy meeting, which gouged desired for a fast approaching ascent in US rates.

Little change has been seen in spot gold since Thursday, while US gold futures for December delivery were $1.90 at $1,531.30.

Naeem Aslam, the Chief market analyst at Ava Trade says “The massive move we have experienced during the past couple of days … was primarily on the back of dollar softness and qualms around emerging markets.”

“The Chinese economic date release today has also helped the metal, as this presages more headwinds for the Fed.”

“However, now we do need a new catalyst to drive the price any higher and next week’s economic date could certainly fulfill this craving.”

Gold has gone under overwhelming pressure this year from possibility that the Fed would raise rates without precedent for about 10 years, lifting the open door expense of holding non-yielding bullion while boosting the dollar.

Wall Street plunged at the open, tumbling for the fourth straight session, as the information from China unnerved investors already stressed over the pace of worldwide development.

The voracity for danger was further scratched in Europe after Greek Prime Minister Alexis Tsipras stepped down from his position on Thursday.

Gold may very well stay bolstered in the transient by further short-covering and safe-haven demands.

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/123.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/20140221-gold.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>gold-set-for-its-most-sizable-climb-since-january-as-stocks-and-the-dollar-slide</slug>
		<Date>20150821</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>315</id>
		<title>Happy 2015 Diwali</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Happy-Deepavali-Wishes-Images.jpg"><img class="wp-image-316 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Happy-Deepavali-Wishes-Images.jpg" alt="Happy-Deepavali-Wishes-Images" width="342" height="299" /></a>

&nbsp;

Bullion Exchanges is pleased to offer the <strong><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/1-oz-pamp-suisse-gold-bar-lakshmi-in-assay-9999-fine">PAMP Suisse Gold Lakshmi Bar (In Assay)</a></strong> in multiple denominations and available for purchase today, just in time for the Festival of Lights!

Diwali is recognized as one of the most significant festivals in Indian culture, not just for the excitement and abundance that Diwali is known for, but also for the customs including the adorning of homes and businesses with oil lamps, decorating the streets with lavish bowls filled with water and flowers, and ritual baths with fragrant oils. Traditionally, most purchase new clothing, jewelry, and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/catalogsearch/result/?cat=0&amp;q=gold+bars">elaborate gifts</a> in celebration of the Festival of Lights.

Diwali, takes place this year from November 11-15. This lively celebration observed throughout India with dedication and pride, honors the triumph of good over malevolence and learning over a life of obscurity.

Numerous intriguing legends, ceremonies and traditions are connected to the festival, however the most widely recognized legend is of the arrival of Rama Ayodhya following fourteen years of banishment and the demise of Narakasura at the hand of Krishna. For a period of five days Diwali customs and traditions that include the lighting of oil lamps, filling the skies with vibrant firecrackers, worshipping cattle which are regarded as a source of wealth and godliness, decorating homes with colorful Rangoli, and Lakshmi Puja are performed with devotion!

Lakshmi Puja takes place on the third day of Diwali, it is on this day that prayers are devoted to the<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/catalogsearch/result/?cat=0&amp;q=gold+lakshmi"> Goddess Lakshmi</a>, the goddess of riches and success. Tradition dictates that Lakshmi will frequent the houses of her believers to shower them with blessings. In hopes of being showered with goddesses affections, a Puja or ritual prayer is offered to Goddess Lakshmi during the evening in each home.

A common tradition during the festival of Diwali is the exchange of gifts, with gold being the most highly favored indulgence. Gold is not just a metal in India or purely for investing, it holds incredible nostalgic worth to the people of India for cultural reasons. Gifting gold is customary in many Indian celebrations, it is considered favorable to purchase gold during holidays like Diwali.

Bestow the gift of good fortune upon your loved ones with the <a href="http://PAMP Suisse Gold Lakshmi Bar">PAMP Suisse Gold Lakshmi Bar</a>, available through Bullion Exchanges in its original packaging. This exceptional bar is available in 10 gram, 1 oz, and 5 gram gold weights.

Be sure to check out the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/catalogsearch/result/?cat=0&amp;q=silver+lakshmi">Silver PAMP Suisse Lakshmi Bar (In Assay)</a> and similar <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/catalogsearch/result/?cat=0&amp;q=silver+bars">silver products</a> today!

Buying gold in celebration of Diwali? Call Bullion Exchanges at (212) 354-1517 for assistance, our associates are happy to address any questions, or concerns you may have prior to completing your purchase. We are also available by e-mail, online using our live chat feature, or in person at our retail location in the heart of New York City’s iconic Diamond District. Booming since the 1940’s, Bullion Exchanges has made this trusted block the home of our operations. Bullion collectors and investors, all of the products featured on our website can be purchased at 32- West 47<sup>th</sup> Street, Booth 41-46, New York, NY 10036 and our hours of operation are from Monday - Friday 9AM-5PM or you can order via our website <a href="http://www.bullionexchanges.com">www.bullionexchanges.com</a> 24/7/365 days a year.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Happy-Deepavali-Wishes-Images.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text></image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>happy-2015-diwali</slug>
		<Date>20151110</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>334</id>
		<title>Black Friday/Cyber Monday Bullion Blowout!</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/event_image_55400d9cb38dd.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-335 alignright" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/event_image_55400d9cb38dd.jpg" alt="event_image_55400d9cb38dd" width="400" height="400" /></a>

&nbsp;

Black Friday marks the official start of the holiday shopping extravaganza, and Bullion Exchanges is your direct source to early and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/10-oz-republic-metals-rmc-silver-bar-999-fine-sealed">attractive deals</a>!

Though the name ‘Black Friday’ may have been coined in the early 1960s, it turns out to have been an unofficial holiday since as early as 1924, during the commencement of the Macy’s Thanksgiving Day Parade, and has been celebrated by savvy shoppers every year since with the addition of Cyber Monday which allows people to take advantage of the sales online.

Studies anticipate that the 2015 holiday season will yield sales upwards of $600,000,000,000 with significant contributions from Thanksgiving deals. With such massive sales anticipated, it is crucial to plan ahead which will ensure you get the most for your money.

Today, Bullion Exchanges is thrilled to offer a <a href="https://bullionexchanges.com/deals">wide selection of products</a> at a discounted price ahead of the Black Friday/Cyber Monday Rush! Our comprehensive collection has been handpicked to suit the likes of both our seasoned investors and holiday shoppers!

Our Black Friday/Cyber Monday Bullion Blowout includes but is not limited to the latest <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/all-silver-products/2016-1-oz-silver-canadian-maple-leaf-9999-fine-5-coin-bu">2016 coins </a>to be released. Check out our full selection of sale items for the best prices and take advantage of the opportunity to add large quantities of bullion to your collection!

Enjoy free shipping on all US orders and hassle free returns with Black Friday/Cyber Monday deals at Bullion Exchanges.

If you have any questions about the products or special prices being offered by Bullion Exchanges, please feel free to e-mail us at <a href="mailto:info@bullionexchanges.com">info@bullionexchanges.com</a> or use our Live Chat feature to reach out to our expert team of associated.

Shop online, and get free shipping or in-store pickup to beat the arduous checkout line journey!

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/event_image_55400d9cb38dd.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text></image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>black-fridaycyber-monday-bullion-blowout</slug>
		<Date>20151125</Date>
		<category>Market News</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>376</id>
		<title>Proof American Gold Eagles 2016 Launch</title>
		<content><![CDATA[March 17 saw the release of four new 2016-W Proof American Gold Eagles Coins by the <a href="https://www.usmint.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">United States Mint</a>. The impressive collection of America Gold Eagles collectibles is sold in sizes of <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-w-1-oz-proof-gold-american-eagle-w-box-coa">1 oz.</a>, <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-w-1-2-oz-proof-gold-american-eagle-w-box-coa">1/2 oz.</a>, <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-w-1-4-oz-proof-gold-american-eagle-w-box-coa">1/4 oz.</a> and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-w-1-10-oz-proof-gold-american-eagle-w-box-coa">1/10 oz.</a> which correspond to the denominations of $50, $25, $10 and $5. Ever since 1986, there has been the release of similarly designed Gold Eagles coins by the US. Mint. The U.S Mint offers the coins individually as well as a <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-w-4-coin-proof-gold-american-eagle-set-w-box-coa">set of all four coins</a>.

<img class="alignleft wp-image-379" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/2016-W-oz-Proof-Gold-American-Eagle.jpg" alt="2016 Proof American Gold Eagles" width="388" height="388" />

&nbsp;

Each exquisitely crafted, proof gold eagle coin is struck in 22-karat gold and is accompanied by an authenticity certificate. The proof coins all bear the 'W' mint marks of the West Point Mint with a mirror-like surface and frosted design.

On the obverse (head side) of the coin, the Augustus Saint-Gaudens’ image of Liberty is featured against the Capitol building, stretching rays of sunlight with an inscription of 2016 and the 'W' mint mark. Surrounding this design is the word 'LIBERTY'  and 50 stars. Miss Liberty is imprinted with a lit torch in the right and an olive branch in her left hand with her hair flowing.

The reverse, however, features an image by Miley Frances Busiek of a family of eagles - a female eagle and her eaglets. Whilst a male eagle flies towards the nested family. The image is surrounded on top by 'UNITED STATES OF AMERICA' on the sides by 'IN GOD WE TRUST' and 'E PLURIBUS UNUM' and on the bottom by 'the coin's gold value and legal tender value'.

If you have questions please do not hesitate to contact us. Our customer service team is available by phone at <a href="tel:800.852.6884">800.852.6884</a>. You can also connect with us through use of our live chat feature, or send us a message at <a href="mailto:info@bullionexchanges.com">info@bullionexchanges.com</a>.]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/2016-W-oz-Proof-Gold-American-Eagle.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>2016 Proof American Gold Eagles</image_alt_text>
		<tags>Gold Eagles|Proof Gold Coins</tags>
		<slug>proof-american-gold-eagles-2016-launch</slug>
		<Date>20160407</Date>
		<category>New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>401</id>
		<title><![CDATA[The Royal Canadian Mint's latest security enhancements]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;">Dealers, collectors, and investors have always been concerned about the authenticity of their precious metal investments. For this reason, many world-renowned mints have focused their efforts on the implementation of forefront technologies to enhance the security of their bullion products.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Royal Canadian Mint is one of the few mints to have successfully applied several proven techniques which stand against counterfeiting and ease the bullion verification process. On the 16</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of May 2016, RCM made one more step towards reinforcing their famed craftsmanship by introducing the latest security measures for their new 2016 1 Oz. 99.99% Gold Bar.</span>

<img class="size-full wp-image-406 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/royal-canadian-mint-security-features.jpg" alt="royal-canadian-mint-security-features" width="478" height="332" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Royal Canadian Mint is a well-known precious metals refiner and manufacturer, worldwide recognized for its thorough approach to implementing the most innovative security measures.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">This prestigious mint released the new 2016 1 Oz. 99.99% Gold Bar, which has carried the same weight, size and purity content, since debuting in 1999. What makes it truly special is that the new 1 Oz. Gold Bar includes the latest three RCM security enhancements:</span>
<ul>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>The uniform striking line pattern</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – present on both the obverse and reverse side of the bar – being, at the same time, an exquisite touch of contemporary design and an added security feature;</span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>The state-of-the-art micro laser-engraved maple leaf</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> –  already used for the iconic Gold and Silver Maple Leaf coins;<img class="alignright size-full wp-image-402" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/rcm-security-features.jpg" alt="rcm-security-features" width="80" height="78" /></span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>The micro-engraved “16” inscription inside the maple leafs</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – ensuring the authentication of the bar through this new inventive way of displaying its mintage year.</span></li>
</ul>
<span style="font-weight: 400;">The packaging of these outstanding RCM Gold Bars was also redesigned, mimicking the new lined pattern, on the front side, along with the assay certificate on the back side of the tamper-proof card.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Royal Canadian Mint has already used these bullion security enhancements for its most popular precious metals products. The stunning radial line pattern and the micro-engraved maple leaf privy mark were first introduced for the 2014 releases of the Silver Maple Leaf coin. One year later, the mint started to strike the Gold Maple Leaf coin using the same micro-engraved mark and sunburst radial lines, creating an eye-catching light-diffracting pattern and exclusive luster to these already  famous coins.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The latest RCM bullion products to receive the new design and security upgrades are the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/1-kilo-republic-metals-rmc-gold-bar-9999-fine-w-assay">1 Kilo Gold Bar</a> and the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/100-oz-republic-metals-rmc-silver-bar-999-fine">100 oz. Silver Bar</a>. Each of these bars is stamped with an individual serial number, the mint’s logo and the hallmarked maple leaf, placed on both sides of the weight stamp. These marks have a raised center and a depressed outline similar to the laser engraved privy mark on Silver and Gold Maple Leaf coin. Also, the serial number on the bars is bordered by vertical lines just like the pattern of the maple leaf.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">Another one-of-a-kind Royal Canadian Mint security initiative is their Bullion DNA Anti-counterfeiting technology launched in 2014. This cutting-edge technology is based on the unique morphological features of each bullion round, aimed to distinguish fake gold coins, as well as silver editions, from authentic Maple Leaf Coins.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">To achieve the exclusive textured maple leaf mark, which contains the last two digits of the mintage year which are only visible under magnification, the mint laser-engraves the mark on the dies that are used for striking Gold and Silver Maple Leaf Coins. Then, through use of Digital Non-destructive Activation (DNA) technology, the mint converts, encrypts and registers, in its secure database, a special digital code for every die, which is obtained by capturing a microscopic view of each die’s mark.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">Therefore, when the Bullion DNA is used in store for identifying any fake maple leaf coin, the security mark of the real coin acts as a fingerprint and matches the complex digital code within the RCM die register, thus confirming its authenticity.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">This leading edge strategy of the Royal Canadian Mint enhances the protection of its exclusive precious metal bars and coins, thereby ensuring the safety of your future investments.</span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/royal-canadian-mint-security-features.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/rcm-security-features.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>royal-canadian-mint-security-features|rcm-security-features</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>royal-canadian-mint-latest-security-enhancements-new-1-oz-gold-bar</slug>
		<Date>20160531</Date>
		<category>Market News|New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>463</id>
		<title>Gold: Multi-Decade Breakout Underway</title>
		<content><![CDATA[The mainstream media is largely missing the significance of the moves we are now seeing in the precious metals sector.

Most readers will already be familiar with the fundamental factors impacting gold and silver prices: unsustainable government debt, negative interest rates, unwinnable overseas wars, and a worldwide fiat currency system that has no precedent in history.

Yet the focus of our work here is not to simply repeat the headlines impacting the day-to-day price of gold. For as we have seen from the 2011-2015 drop in precious metals, one can be very right on the fundamentals impacting the market, yet prices can move in the opposite direction for a prolonged period.

We must instead let the market tell us what it wants to do, and therefore we turn to a long-term technical perspective in order to observe the trends in gold.

<strong>Gold's Long-Term Pattern</strong>

Gold has just successfully retested its breakout from a multi-decade consolidation dating between 1980 and 2009, almost three decades during which the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">price</a> was held below $850 per troy ounce. The significance of such a breakout cannot be overstated: multi-decade consolidations and breakouts usually lead to multi-decade advances, with targets many times the previous consolidation high. When we view examples throughout history of markets that have experienced similar consolidations and advances, we see that in percentage terms gold in the mid-$1300 range has only just begun to move toward its full potential.

<strong><img class="alignnone wp-image-461" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Gold-price-between-1980-and-2009.png" alt="Gold-price-1980-2009" width="1136" height="500" /></strong>

<strong>A Historical Example in the Dow</strong>

The potential for a market that consolidates for several decades and then breaks out successfully must be appreciated. Let us view an example from history of a well-known market that went through a multi-decade consolidation and successful breakout, so as to assess the ramifications of this pattern for gold.

From 1959 to 1982, the <a href="https://www.google.com/finance?cid=983582">Dow Jones Industrial Average</a> consolidated between roughly 550 and just over 1,000 points. It was a choppy consolidation, but it featured a clearly defined resistance zone near 1,000, as can be seen on the chart below. For these 23 years, no one with a buy and hold strategy for US stocks made much money, and many investors gave up hope of ever making a profit.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-462" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/1959-1982-Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average.png" alt="1959-1982-Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average" width="757" height="500" />

However, in 1982 the Dow finally broke out above 1,000, hitting 1,300 in the fall of 1983. Its retest of the former 1,000 resistance zone was quick, lasting from late 1983 to mid 1984, and in fact, did not fall completely back to that exact price, only briefly touching 1,100 for a low.

Once that retest proved successful, the advance was quick to accelerate. The rest, as they say, was history, as one of the greatest bull markets continued on for <em>almost as long as the consolidation</em> -- 18 years total -- and achieved <em>over a 1,000% gain from the previous all-time high </em>(hitting 11,500 in the year 2000)<em>.</em>

<img class="alignnone wp-image-464" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-increase.png" alt="Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-increase" width="666" height="500" />

<strong>Back to Gold</strong>

Gold is now positioned similarly to where the Dow was in mid-1984, when it successfully retested the 1,000 level after breaking out from its multi-decade consolidation. Gold's retest occurred in December of last year, at $1,045 per ounce.

Let us rewind the specific chronology for gold that we are referring to:

Gold peaked in 1980 near $850 per troy once, only to fall back to $255 by the year 2000 after a series of rallies and further drops.

It then took gold nine years to climb back up to $850 and exceed that level for good.

We thus view the entire 1980 - 2009 period as a multi-decade consolidation below the $850 level, and the final break above this figure as the completion of this pattern. Again, multi-decade consolidations are rare formations in the capital markets, and they usually lead to advances that measure similar amounts of time.

After gold's breakout in 2009 it surged for two more years only, hitting a new peak in 2011 at $1,923.

The bear market from 2011 - 2015 occurred entirely above the multi-decade $850/oz consolidation, and thus constitutes a retest of the former high in technical analysis.

Note that gold, similar to the Dow, has shown relative strength by not falling all the way to the $850 level for its retest, instead forming a clear bottom at $1,045 in December 2015.

Gold subsequently broke out of its primary downtrend in late February (shown by the turquoise-color channel on the main chart above), and has just had its best six-month performance gain in 40 years, with a 24% advance from January through June 2016. We now zoom in on the final part of the bear market, and the breakout seen in February.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-465 size-large" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Gold-price-chart-2014-2016-1024x766.png" alt="Gold-price-chart-2014-2016" width="840" height="628" />

<strong>The Potential for Gold </strong>

To continue with the Dow analogy above, we are looking for an advance beginning in gold that should last for a similar length of time as the consolidation from 1980-2009. In other words, a multi-decade bull market in the precious metals sector is likely now starting.

While history does not repeat exactly in markets or in life, it often rhymes.

Thus, long-term investors in the precious metals would do well to take a step back from the day-to-day price fluctuations and truly contemplate the potential presented by the first chart in this article. While volatility and corrections should always be expected in any market, we believe there is a major opportunity now unfolding in the precious metals sector.

Trying to put exact numbers on a price target at this moment can only diminish the message of the underlying strength gold is showing. But for comparison purposes, if the precious metal were to achieve an 11-fold move above it's previous all-time high as the Dow did from 1982 - 2000, it would give us a target of over $9,000 per ounce. This would happen within the timespan of the next few decades.

Our point in this piece is not to encourage readers to obsess over the final target, but rather to see this market within the context of the unique multi-decade breakout that is currently unfolding.

This pattern is rare and powerful in the financial markets, and gold is positioned at the beginning of the setup right now.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.

Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.

His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-increase.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Gold-price-chart-2014-2016.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-increase|Gold-price-chart-2014-2016</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>gold-multi-decade-breakout-underway</slug>
		<Date>20160711</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>522</id>
		<title>Silver - Fundamentals Reveal Large Potential</title>
		<content><![CDATA[While we tend to focus on technical indicators in our analysis of the precious metals, in this article we will examine the fundamentals drivers within the silver market.

What are the trends amongst miners, scrappers, hedgers, jewelers, industrialists, and investors? What can we see setting up for silver -- a historically monetary metal, now with significant industrial demand -- over the next decade?

Our review follows: we are more bullish than ever on <strong>silver prices</strong> and believe that the moves we have seen over the last 10 years are a mere preview of the price level that is to come over the next decade. However, investors should expect high volatility, with 25-35% price swings every year going forward.

<strong>A Review of Silver's Fundamentals</strong>

A review of the fundamental case for silver reveals a bullish scenario for those investors with at least a several year timespan and the tolerance for this high volatility.

The scenario centers on an investment premium now being priced into a historically monetary metal that concurrently has the backdrop of significant industrial demand. This industrial demand is mostly inelastic at or even above current prices.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-524" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/a_Silverfundamentals.jpg" alt="world-silver-supply-demand" width="1500" height="1125" />

<strong>Mine Supply Growing Slowly</strong>

In reviewing the past ten years of data for silver (courtesy Thompson Reuters / The Silver Institute), we find overall supply that has increased 13% since 2006 to over one billion ounces per year (first orange row on chart above). Of that, mine supply has seen consistent year over year production increases to 886M oz., while government sales have flat lined, and scrap production is down 29% over the same time period.

The data shows that mine production is the key supply source, accounting for nearly 85% of the market. This mine supply, while slowly increasing, cannot respond to quick changes in demand, as the exploration-development-extraction lifecycle for mining companies can take well over a decade to bring new silver to the market.

<strong>Silver Fabrication Demand is Inelastic</strong>

Turning to the demand side, we see that net physical demand for silver has increased roughly 13% in the past 10 years, again to over a billion ounces per year (second orange row on the chart above). While silverware use is flat and overall industrial fabrication is down slightly, zooming in on the details here gives us much more insight as to the emerging long-term trends.

The bulk of the industrial drop comes from photographic use for silver, which has fallen by over 67%, to a low of 46 million ounces in 2015. At the same time, electronic fabrication is up 2% to 246M oz., and photovoltaic use has gone from negligible to over 77M oz.

<em>The key then is to note that the bulk of the industrial drop has already occurred</em> -- in the photographic category. At current decline rates, it will only take a few more years for photographic use to be negligible. <strong>The rest of the industrial side taken as a sum shows increased demand over the last 10 years.</strong>

This increased industrial demand is largely inelastic, as can be seen by the fact that the increase has occurred during a time when silver prices have moved from an average of $6 per ounce to nearly $20 today. The reason for the inelasticity is that for most industrial applications, there is not a suitable replacement for silver. For example: in solar panels, computers, and cell phones, the total cost for silver in the manufactured components is such a small fraction of the overall materials cost, yet so essential for production, that it does not matter whether the price is $6, $20, or significantly higher.

There exists no acceptable substitute.

<strong>Silver Investment Demand is the Key Price Driver</strong>

On the investment side (highlighted in green on the chart above), the most significant item to note is that demand for coins and bars has risen nearly six-fold over the last decade to 292M oz. This demand sits at the margin, and is by far the most variable; for example falling 35% from 2011 to 2012, before rising 82% from 2012 to 2015 to the highest demand on record, 292M oz.

Yet despite the variability, the trend is clear over the last decade: silver is being demanded increasingly as an investment store of value.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-530" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/silver-fabrication-indices.jpg" alt="silver-fabrication-indices" width="840" height="693" />

<strong>Speculation as the Art of Profit</strong>

Speculation is the nature of all investment. To make a profit as investors, we must have a belief that is above and beyond what is currently accepted by the mainstream. We must view more perspective, or know more information, than the sum of the other market participants in order for there to be a discrepancy in prices. It is only in discrepancy between current prices and future prices there is the potential for gain.

So let us speculate for a moment.

Why is silver seeing this recent increase in investment demand? Why are there six times as many investment dollars buying <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver/bars">silver bars</a> and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver/coins">coins</a> now compared to a decade ago?

Our analysis is that silver is regaining some of its historic monetary role. Indeed, for most of the history of human civilization, while gold has traditionally served as a store of wealth, silver has been used for smaller monetary exchanges. To this day in Spanish, the word for silver is the same as the word for money ('plata'). It is only since 1965, when the last U.S. quarters and dimes containing <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver/junk-silver">90% silver</a> were removed from circulation, that silver has not had a direct monetary role. We thus exist in what can be viewed as a 50-year 'experiment' in human history with silver not serving as money.

As a society, have we progressed for the first time to such an advanced level that silver is permanently relegated to a relic of monetary history? Or, does human nature move in repeating cycles, with silver beginning to reemerge as a store of value after several decades out of favor?

We turn to the market for answers. Judging from the increase in investment demand, we can see that the metal is regaining something of a monetary premium. And while the growth over the last decade is impressive, it still amounts to only 292M oz. purchased worldwide every year.

<strong>What is the Potential for Investment Demand?</strong>

To put the size of the worldwide investable silver market into perspective, 292M oz. purchased per year equates to roughly $5.8 billion.

The market cap of Apple Computer alone is over $550 billion.

Let us ask a few reasonable questions:
<ol>
 	<li>What would happen if each of the 100M households in the United States wanted to own 10 ounces of silver next year ($200 per household)? Such would equate to one billion ounces of silver demand.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
 	<li>With jewelry/silverware/industrial use consuming over 80% of the one billion ounce supply at any price, where would that silver come from?</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
 	<li>Moreover, what if one billion of the world's 7.3 billion residents each wanted to own a single ounce per year for the next three years?</li>
</ol>
The silver is simply not there at current prices. A major revaluation would have to occur should any additional significant demand come into the market.

Turning our attention to the long-term <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/silver-price">silver chart</a>, note the increasing price spikes every few years (2006, 2008, 2011) with a rising linear up trend line (shown in magenta) acting as support.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-527" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/silver-price-1980-present.png" alt="silver-price-1980-present" width="1240" height="737" />

Amidst a rising mine supply and stable industrial/jewelry/silverware demand, it <em>must be the physical investment</em> demand that has caused these price spikes, as every few years a new wave of investors moves into the silver market.

<strong>Silver Price Projections</strong>

Our analysis is that silver has formed a long-term bottom in the $13 - $16 price range.

From this bottom, the trend is clear: silver is regaining a monetary/investment premium after several decades of mostly fabrication use. That fabrication demand is inelastic. The investment demand for silver is what exists at the margin, and has been the primary driver in higher silver price spikes seen over the last decade. Economic cycles tend to move in waves over time, and when a small percentage of the world's population decides to invest only a tiny fraction of its combined wealth into silver, we anticipate the price will rise to a multiple of the current level.

Our initial 3-5 year target is a retest of $50/oz. This has been a multi-decade resistance level. Once this level is broken decisively, we anticipate it will act like a floor, just as the $850 level has for gold and the $1.20 level has for copper. From there, we may reevaluate our thesis as fundamental factors warrant.

For those investors with at least a several-year time horizon and a tolerance for high volatility, the opportunity in silver looks quite significant -- from a technical and a fundamental viewpoint.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000’s. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.

Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.

His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/silver-fabrication-indices.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/silver-fabrication-indices-1.tiff|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/silver-price-1980-present.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/silver-fabrication-indices.tiff|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/b_SilverFabrication.tiff|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/a_Silverfundamentals.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>silver-fabrication-indices||silver-price-1980-present|silver-fabrication-indices|silver-fabrication-indices|world-silver-supply-demand</image_alt_text>
		<tags>silver price</tags>
		<slug>silver-fundamentals-reveal-large-potential</slug>
		<Date>20160718</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>539</id>
		<title>The new 2016 1 oz. Platinum American Eagle BU Coin is now available at Bullion Exchanges</title>
		<content><![CDATA[The US Mint just released the 2016 edition of the official platinum bullion coin of the United States – the 1 oz. Platinum American Eagle BU Coin. This outstanding coin is expected to sell out quickly because the US Mint plans to make only one batch of coins for the entire issue.

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-406 size-full" title="2016-1-oz-platinum-american-eagle-front" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/front_2016_1_oz_Platinum_American_Eagle.jpg" alt="2016 1 oz platinum american eagle front" width="478" />
<h5>The obverse side of the 2016 1 oz. Platinum Eagle BU Coin designed by John Mercanti</h5>
The brand-new <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-1-oz-platinum-american-eagle-bu">2016 1 oz. Platinum American Eagle BU Coin</a> is available to be ordered in individual plastic flips, as well as in 20-coin tubes and white monster boxes of 100 coins. Bullion Exchanges is also proud to offer you the exclusive 2016 1 oz Platinum American Eagle NGC MS 69 Early Releases and 2016 1 oz Platinum American Eagle NGC MS 70 Early Releases.

<em><strong>Important!</strong> The US Mint advised its official distributors that the new 1 oz. BU Platinum American Eagle will be issued under one production run and no additional coins are planned to be produced after the first batch of coins gets sold out. This decision may significantly impact the demand for this iconic coin, making it more collectible to numismatists and investors</em>.

<center><strong>Get your <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-1-oz-platinum-american-eagle-bu">2016 1 oz. Platinum American Eagle Brilliant Uncirculated Coin</a> today, before it is sold out!</strong></center>The US Mint released the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-platinum/coins/american-platinum-eagle">Platinum American Eagle Coin</a> program in 1997 and during their mintage period, these coins have been struck in various sizes and options at the West Point and Philadelphia facilities. The 1 oz. BU Platinum American Eagle is produced of 1.0005 troy ounce of .9995 pure Platinum, has a diameter of 32.7 mm, reeded edges and preserves its original mint luster. This exceptional platinum coin is legal tender and bears a face value of $100 USD, guaranteed by the United States Government, however its bullion value is much higher.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-599" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/1-oz-Platinum-Eagle-Coin-BU-Coin-Sales-1997-2014_2.jpg" alt="1 oz Platinum-Eagle-Coin-BU-Coin-Sales-1997-2014" width="1972" height="1550" />

Production of 1 oz. Platinum Eagle Non-Proof Coins has decreased<b> </b>significantly since 1998, which makes these coins rare and adds to their numismatic value.

On the obverse side of the coin is depicted the “Portrait of Liberty” image, created by the Chief Sculptor-Engraver of the US Mint – John Mercanti. This design is struck on the bullion, uncirculated and proof American Eagle Coins since their debut, and represents the image of the Statue of Liberty gazing with confidence, surrounded by the engravings “2016”, “Liberty”, “In God We Trust” and “E Pluribus Unum”.

Unlike the proof edition of this stunning coin, the reverse image of the Brilliant Uncirculated Platinum Eagles doesn’t change. It depicts the magnificent bald eagle, with its wings outstretched while soaring against the sunrise. Its image is encircled by the inscriptions “$100”, “United States of America” and the engravings of the weight and purity of the coin. This impressive design was created by Thomas D. Rodgers Sr. and makes this coin a truly national coinage icon.

<center><strong>Add this fantastic <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-1-oz-platinum-american-eagle-bu">2016 1 oz. Platinum American Eagle BU Coin</a> to your portfolio today!</strong></center><img class="size-full wp-image-406 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/back_2016_1_oz_Platinum_American_Eagle.jpg" alt="2016 1 oz platinum american eagle back" width="478" />
<h5>The reverse side of the 2016 1 oz. Platinum Eagle BU Coin designed by Thomas D. Rodgers Sr.</h5>
<strong>Why you should consider buying this remarkable platinum coin?</strong>

About ten times rarer than gold, platinum is regarded as an expensive precious metal, although over the last two years it has been traded at a lower price than gold. Along with palladium, platinum is a relative new precious metal discovered by Spanish in South America in 1735 and today, over 80% of the platinum is mined exclusively in Russia and South Africa. Besides, this precious metal is also used in jewelry and automobile industries. For this reasons, platinum bullion products are usually considered as rare collectibles and highly sought-after precious metal items.

<em>The purpose of this Bullion Exchanges article is purely informative and shall not be considered as an investment recommendation or advice.</em>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/front_2016_1_oz_Platinum_American_Eagle-e1469117012429.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/1-oz-Platinum-Eagle-Coin-BU-Coin-Sales-1997-2014_2.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/back_2016_1_oz_Platinum_American_Eagle.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>front_2016_1_oz_Platinum_American_Eagle|1 oz Platinum-Eagle-Coin-BU-Coin-Sales-1997-2014|</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>2016-1-oz-platinum-american-eagle-bu-coin-released</slug>
		<Date>20160721</Date>
		<category>New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>581</id>
		<title>Analysis: Gold to Dow Ratio</title>
		<content><![CDATA[The US stock market hit a new all-time high this week as fears that the Brexit fallout would spill across the Atlantic subsided somewhat. Given the strength seen in the world's largest equity market, and that we are now directly within the seasonally-weakest time period of the year for the precious metals, it is not unexpected to see some funds shift out of <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold </a>and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver">silver</a> and into US stocks.

Below we show the US Dow Jones Industrial Average, from the crash lows of 2009 through the present. Note how prices have just this week spiked above the 18500 level, the previous high from 2015.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-582" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/US-Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-2009-2016.png" alt="US-Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-2009-2016" width="1240" height="928" />

Yet generally, the proper strategy to make a solid return in the markets is not to follow the crowd and chase the best-performing assets of the last several years. Rather, the best strategy is typically to take the contrarian perspective and to try to find out what most people are ignoring.

We must remember that the chart above shows US stocks <u>priced in US dollars.</u>

As we know, the US dollar is a depreciating currency (as are all world currencies). So in the chart above we are not looking at a stable-value measure for the Dow.

It would thus be beneficial to also see the Dow as compared to another form of money: gold.

Below we show the value of the Dow compared to gold since 1980. This ratio asks: how many shares of the Dow Jones Industrial Average does it take to buy one ounce of gold?

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-583" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Dow-to-gold-ratio.png" alt="Dow-to-gold-ratio" width="1240" height="737" />

Currently it takes 0.070 shares of the Dow to buy one ounce of gold.

The all-time low value for gold relative to the Dow was set in the year 1999 when it took only 0.024 shares of the Dow to buy the same ounce.

In contrast, the all-time high for the ratio was set in 1980 at 1.00. This was at the last generational precious metals peak when, for a short period, the price of gold topped $850 per ounce and the Dow was also priced at 850.

With this historical perspective, what can we say about the current price of gold?

<strong>Gold is nowhere near a long-term peak.</strong>

In fact, gold is priced much closer to its 1999 bottom than its 1980 peak as measured against the Dow.

For example, if the ratio was to hit 1.00 again, and the Dow was to simply maintain its current value, gold would have to be re-priced to $18,500 per ounce.

Should the Dow lose half it's value and fall to 9250, gold would still need to rise 7-fold to reach this same number.

Both of these examples would feature a nominal return to the 1.00 ratio between gold and the Dow as seen in 1980.

<strong>Ratios Repeat Throughout History</strong>

Further, the 1980 peak was not the only time in history that this ratio hit 1.00.

In 1933, when gold was confiscated from American citizens by President Roosevelt and revalued during the Great Depression from $20 to $35 per ounce, the Dow Jones Industrial Average had fallen from its peak of 400 all the way to the upper 30's.

<img class="alignnone wp-image-597" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/djia.png" alt="Dow-Jones-Average-1933-crash_" width="575" height="443" />

The gold to Dow ratio in the early 1930's thus stood at nearly 1.00.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-585" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/d_Gold_conf.jpeg" alt="Dow -ratio-1933" width="1128" height="736" />

We therefore have multiple data points throughout history of precious metals peaks in which the Dow and gold were valued the same in nominal terms. Currently at 18,500 and $1,315 respectively, clearly we are not in the territory of a long-term top in gold.

It will be important over the coming months to keep the Gold-Dow ratio in mind if we see some continued consolidation in the precious metals, and further advances in US stocks. The mainstream media will likely be fully endorsing the move higher in stocks (after all, most media conglomerates are public companies whose shares are included in the stock indices -- they thus have much to gain by encouraging individuals to bid their shares higher).

Yet those with a little historic perspective will let these moves unfold as they surely must. Even at $1,315, gold is priced closer to a bottom than a top compared to major stock markets. The reversion to a historic valuation ratio that has occurred multiple times in the past will occur again. Those who understand this phenomenon of reversion to the mean will continue to quietly accumulate gold and related assets even as the mainstream financial press focuses on the nominal new highs being made in the US stock market.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.

Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.

His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/d_Gold_conf.jpeg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/djia.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Dow-Jones-Average-1933-crash.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-1933-crash.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-1929-crash.gif|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Dow-to-gold-ratio.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/US-Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-2009-2016.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>Dow -ratio-1933|Dow-Jones-Average-1933-crash_|Dow-Jones-Average-1933-crash|Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-1933-crash|Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-1929-crash|Dow-to-gold-ratio|US-Dow-Jones-Industrial-Average-2009-2016</image_alt_text>
		<tags>gold price</tags>
		<slug>gold-to-dow-ratio</slug>
		<Date>20160725</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>603</id>
		<title>Gold Surges After Fed Meeting</title>
		<content><![CDATA[The primary driver for the precious metals last week was the Federal Reserve meeting, which concluded on Wednesday. At the meeting, the Fed once again left interest rates unchanged, at generationally-low levels targeting 0.25% - 0.50%.

Even more important than the lack of change in the target rate was the Fed's statement regarding inflation following the decision:

<em>"</em><em>Inflation has continued to run below the Committee's 2 percent longer-run objective, partly reflecting earlier declines in energy prices and in prices of non-energy imports. Market-based measures of inflation compensation remain low; most survey-based measures of longer-term inflation expectations are little changed, on balance, in recent months. "</em>

In essence, when the Fed comments that inflation expectations are low, it is signaling that it intends to spark more inflation (i.e. print more money). Gold and silver, being inflation-sensitive assets, deciphered this language and spiked immediately following the Fed announcement, with <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">gold rising</a> $20 for the day and silver nearly $0.70.

<strong>Fed Policy is Currency Debasement</strong>

It is important to step back for a moment and contemplate some of the policies described in the Fed's meeting statement above. Here we have a central bank explicitly stating that its policy is to debase the currency by 2 percent per year.

<strong>Two percent inflation per year, compounded, results in the currency losing 50% of its value in just 34 years.</strong>

Thus, the Fed's policy is to have savers in US dollars lose 50% of their wealth every generation.

How is it possible that citizens accept such a policy for the international reserve currency?

Our long-term thesis is that, slowly but surely, more individuals will begin to wake up the problems inherent with this official inflation policy. When citizens begin to understand this system, at least some will turn to precious metals as a form of protection. If even a small fraction of the world's population makes this decision, the metals will be forced to revalue upward significantly in the coming years.

Our charts are the maps showing these revaluations as they are occurring in real-time.

<strong>Technical Analysis on Gold</strong>

Gold is now making its second attempt at breaking out from the final long-term downtrend that has held its price in check since 2011. While it is not yet certain that this important technical level will be breached this week, we have some important early-indicator signals coming from related sectors that the expected move is not far off into the future.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Gold-price-2009-present.png" alt="Gold-price-2009-present" width="1240" height="928" />

The first attempt at breaking the long-term magenta-colored downtrend was made one month ago at $1,380, and now, as the trend inherently slopes downward, this second attempt is being seen at a slightly lower price level, near $1,365. (To be safe, we should extend this resistance zone upward to the psychologically-important $1,400 level.)

Let us zoom the above chart in to the 18-month timeframe for a closer examination:

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-605" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-price-2015-2016.png" alt="gold-price-2015-2016" width="1240" height="928" />

To those unfamiliar with technical analysis, the surges and retracements seen in gold recently may appear unpredictable, but with the proper technical lens, we can clearly see where large buyers and sellers are emerging.

Let us not mince words: gold is caught in the crosshairs of a significant technical battle at this exact moment. Support was seen this week after the Fed meeting where we expected, right above the green zone labeled near $1,310. Such was the second time gold has bounced at this level, increasing the validity of the support.

Note that the green support zone and the long-term downtrend are converging into the September - October timeframe. When two technical levels converge, one must necessarily give way to the other.

Moreover, gold is also firmly within the rising royal-blue parallel channel which began at the December 2015 bottom. The lower line from this pattern is rising and will also be meeting with the aforementioned two levels by mid-September.

There are thus at minimum three important technical trends that traders and investors alike are monitoring.

<strong>Clues from the Gold Mining Sector</strong>

Subtle clues are appearing that the converging patterns will result in a breakout for gold.

Below we take a quick side by side comparison of the gold miners (top) versus gold itself (bottom) for the last three months. Note that the gold miners are once again on the verge of breaking through their July highs, whereas gold bullion is still some $20 below its corresponding high.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-606" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-miners-2016.png" alt="gold -miners-2016" width="460" height="667" />

The gold miners are leading the metal since the initial bottom observed last December, and are now giving us a signal that gold itself is setting up for a move higher this fall.

<strong>Long Term Ramifications for a Pending Gold Breakout</strong>

We have made the case in past work that the pending break of this 5-year downtrend in gold will set the sector up for an even more powerful scenario from a multi-decade perspective.

Similar to falling dominos, one pattern's completion triggers another to begin, the completion of which may then trigger additional patterns into the future.

Below is the 36-year perspective for gold in logarithmic format, noting the 5-year gently sloping decline that has taken the distinct shape of a "bull flag" formation. Superimposed onto this image is the textbook definition for this bull flag pattern, for reference.

It is the break of the previously-mentioned 2011-2015 downtrend that will set up the bull flag pattern to initiate.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-607" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-spot-price-2011-2015.png" alt="gold-spot-price-2011-2015" width="1240" height="546" />

Bull flag formations represent a pause in an ongoing bull market. In this case, the 2001-2011 advance is seen as the initial "flag pole" surge, the 2011-2015 decline is seen as the half-way "flag" pause, and what is coming should be an advance roughly equivalent to the initial amplitude of the "flag pole".

The initial surge in gold's case measured $1,650 (the amplitude from 2001-2011), and we derive a target for the bull flag pattern by adding this figure to the most recent low of approximately $1,050.

In summary, when we witness a break of the $1,400 resistance zone, there results a strong probability that gold will see a long-term target of at least $2,700.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.

His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-raise-1.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-raise.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-spot-price-2011-2015.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-miners-2016.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-price-2015-2016.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Gold-price-2009-present.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>gold-raise|gold-raise|gold-spot-price-2011-2015|gold -miners-2016|gold-price-2015-2016|Gold-price-2009-present</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>gold-surges-fed-meeting</slug>
		<Date>20160801</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>621</id>
		<title>Gold Technical Update</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<strong>Gold Technical Update</strong>

Gold has just made its second attempt within the last five weeks at breaking through its long-term downtrend (see long-term charts on the previous article, available <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/2016/08/01/gold-surges-fed-meeting">here</a>), and this opportunity once again proved unsuccessful. This price action increases the validity of the resistance shown by the trend line and its importance as a technical data point. Gold is going to have to prove it can overcome this level for the next leg of the bull market to commence.

Yet despite this short-term weakness, we have several reasons to believe that a breakout will be arriving shortly, and those reasons are presented herein.

Gold rose as high as $1,367 early in the week, but sellers continue to appear just above this level and the price backed off to close at $1,335 on the spot market by Friday afternoon.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-622" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Gold-rose-on-friday.png" alt="Gold-rose-on-friday" width="1240" height="928" />

As is typical, charts can often tell us "what" is setting up in the gold market, but the "why" component usually remains to be seen. So what was the cause of gold's fall on Friday? In this case, the drop was due to the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS) which released a "seasonally-adjusted" jobs report for July showing 255,000 jobs created for the month in the United States.

The term "seasonally-adjusted" means the number was not actually derived from a survey of employers proper, but rather estimated based on a seasonal algorithm that the BLS uses for assumed job creation, resulting from historic seasonal trends.

Interestingly, 2016 has seen the highest assumed seasonal job growth reported by the BLS in the last 10 years, as can be seen below:

<img class="alignnone wp-image-623" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/BLS-seasonal-job-growth-reported.jpg" alt="BLS-seasonal-job growth-reported" width="600" height="260" />

Exactly how they derive this assumed data is a question on many analysts' minds, but regardless of the validity of the figure, the market interpreted the announcement to be largely positive for the US dollar and the US stock market, which both spiked higher. As a result, both gold and silver were sold off.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-624" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c_Aug5.png" alt="c_Aug5" width="972" height="648" />

We now return to the charts to guide us as to what may happen next for gold and the precious metals.

<strong>Gold is "Coiling Up"</strong>

Refer again to the first primary chart of gold at the beginning of this article. Gold is now "coiling up" between strong resistance below the previously-mentioned downtrend, and the strong support which is appearing between $1,285 and $1,306, as shown by the green band. This is labeled "Converging Patterns" on the chart.

Of course, this support zone was the former resistance zone we had been following for nearly 18 months, which, decisively broken in June, is now seeing second-chance buyers step in each time the price retreats to this zone.

When markets coil up in this manner, like a spring being held down -- eventually when released the market will experience a significant move in one direction or another.

In studying the area on the primary <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">gold chart</a> above representing the convergence of the downtrend resistance and the green support zone, we note that the meeting of these two trends does not necessarily have to happen until after January 2017. Technically speaking then, the market could take through the winter to break higher or lower from the convergence of these patterns.

However, in years of studying these charts, we can say that in the majority of cases the convergence will resolve itself in one direction or another before the actual meeting of the trends.

Further, based on 45 years of available data since <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> has traded free from the US dollar standard, the single strongest month of the year for gold is straight ahead: September.

We thus have a high expectation that the breaking of these converging trend patterns is going to take place within the next 4-8 weeks.

<strong>Gold Miners Still Providing Leadership Clues</strong>

The gold miners are still anticipating this breakout in the metal, as shown below by the quick reference between the HUI gold miners index on top and spot gold below.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-625" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d_HUI_Gold.png" alt="gold-miners-anticipating-breakout -aug-2016" width="398" height="585" />

Note that the large cap miners closed the week with a marginal gain, whereas the metal finished lower by Friday. The miners indeed finished at a new 52-week closing weekly high.

This outperformance, subtle though it may seem, is continuing to give us clues regarding the resolution of the metal's converging trend patterns.

<strong>Takeaway on Gold Prices</strong>

Strong support exists between $1,285 and $1,306, while resistance is being seen above $1,365. These price levels are converging on the yearly charts, and when opposing trends converge one or the other must break. At present the seasonal strong period for precious metals is due ahead, and we observe leadership in the gold mining equities. We see a high probability of a <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">gold price</a> breakout within the next 4-8 weeks, with an advance to target $1,450.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/gold-technical-analysis.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d_HUI_Gold.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c_Aug5.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/BLS-seasonal-job-growth-reported.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Gold-rose-on-friday.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>gold-technical-analysis|gold-miners-anticipating-breakout -aug-2016||BLS-seasonal-job growth-reported|Gold-rose-on-friday</image_alt_text>
		<tags>BLS report|gold price</tags>
		<slug>gold-technical-update</slug>
		<Date>20160808</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>632</id>
		<title><![CDATA[Gold's Advance a Worldwide Phenomenon]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[We are continuing to see more evidence that the advance that is ahead of us across the precious metals complex will be a worldwide phenomenon, and not a US dollar-primary event as was seen in the bull market of the 1970's.

<img class="wp-image-646 alignleft" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/a_UKInterest.png" alt="UK-Interest-rate" width="480" height="588" />

This week the Bank of England, clearly responding to the continued tumultuous market conditions since the June 24 Brexit decision, voted to lower short-term interest rates for the first time since 2009. This brings the key lending rate to 0.25%, an all-time record low.

We thus have record low interest rates in the United States, in Europe, and now in England.

Recall that in order for central banks to force interest rates to record lows, they must do so by buying the entire short-end of the bond curve in that country. The money they use to buy those bonds is printed out of thin air, or rather created with the digital equivalent thereof.

Not only does this money creation directly devalue the currency in question, but by holding the short-end of the yield curve down, it forces investors to withdraw funds from low-yield savings accounts or short-term certificates of deposit.

Instead, investors desiring yield are funneled into riskier assets to try to achieve any sort of reasonable income from their capital.

It is any wonder then that the London FTSE 100 stock index is approaching all-time highs? Or that British 10-year government bond yields are approaching all-time lows -- which means their prices are also at all-time highs?

<strong>London FTSE 100 Index since crash of 2008</strong><img class="wp-image-633 size-large aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/b-London-FTSE-100-Index-since-crash-of-2008-819x1024.png" alt="b-London-FTSE 100-Index-since crash-of-2008" width="819" height="1024" />

&nbsp;

<strong>UK Government 10-year Bond Yields</strong>

<img class="wp-image-635 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c-UK-Government-10-year-Bond-Yields.png" alt="UK-Government-10-year-Bond-Yields" width="779" height="699" />

&nbsp;
<h2>Money "sloshing around" the system</h2>
All this freshly-created central bank money is now "sloshing around" the financial and political system, bidding up stock prices, bidding up bonds, bidding up mortgages, funding endless unwinnable wars...

The world has seen several stock-market bubbles over the last 100 years, but has never seen a bond bubble in the way we are now witnessing.

Furthermore, when we study the past we see examples of when certain individual countries have gone down the path of excess money-printing, but we have no examples of a time in which the entire world was engaged in the practice simultaneously.

We are living in an unprecedented time in world history.

What we can conclude based on a study of past asset bubble deflations is that precious metals -- the only store of wealth that politicians or central bankers cannot debase -- will in some way fit into the solution when the bubbles eventually burst.

It is important for us as investors who sometimes focus on the shorter-term patterns setting up in the metals to not lose sight of the unprecedented bigger picture that is developing.

When only a fraction of stock or bond investors, markets which are much larger in total dollar value than <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver">silver</a> combined, decide to move only a fraction of their combined wealth into the precious metals, the upward revaluation will be beyond anything we have witnessed thus far.

It is likely that the 30% <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">surge in gold</a> and the 45% <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/silver-price">surge in silver</a> seen in the last six months represent those early to jump ship from the aforementioned bubble markets and to move some of their capital into the historic metallic stores of wealth. Yet as we see the bubbles still continuing to inflate, we can deduce that we have not yet seen the critical mass begin to move into gold and silver in a meaningful way.
<h2>Update - Gold in Australian Dollars</h2>
We continue to monitor gold as priced in Australian dollars (AUD) as a leading indicator for gold in other major world currencies.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-636" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d-Gold-in-Australian-dollar.png" alt="Gold-in-Australian-dollar" width="1240" height="737" />

The all-time high for gold in AUD was in 2011 at just over $1,850 per ounce. Gold in AUD closed this week at $1,756, less than 6% away from the all-time high.

We have seen 6% surges in gold in one week in the past, so a retest of this level is possible at any time.

When gold decisively breaks to a new all-time high in AUD, it will serve as a signal to the rest of the world that such advances are in store for other major currencies. What was once viewed as a USD-only phenomenon is starting to be recognized in no uncertain terms as worldwide trend in rising gold demand.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Golds-Advance-Worldwide-Phenomenon.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/a_UKInterest.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d-Gold-in-Australian-dollar.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c-UK-Government-10-year-Bond-Yields.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/b-London-FTSE-100-Index-since-crash-of-2008.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>Golds-Advance-Worldwide-Phenomenon|UK-Interest-rate|Gold-in-Australian-dollar|UK-Government-10-year-Bond-Yields|b-London-FTSE 100-Index-since crash-of-2008</image_alt_text>
		<tags>gold price|invest in gold</tags>
		<slug>golds-advance-worldwide-phenomenon</slug>
		<Date>20160815</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>662</id>
		<title><![CDATA[Gold & Silver Technical Update]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[In technical analysis we place a greater emphasis on long-term trendlines for good reason.

For over seven weeks now <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> has continued to bump against its final 2011-2016 downtrend, which has held prices lower since the 2011 high of $1,923 per ounce. Every time it attempts to break higher above this down-sloping resistance level, sellers immediately show up to drive the price back down.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-663" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/a-Gold-2009-present.png" alt="Gold-2009-present" width="1240" height="928" />

There is clearly a battle going on at this exact moment between bulls and bears. Bears know that if this long-term technical resistance level is broken, it will send a signal to the many investors waiting on the sidelines that the time has arrived to jump back into precious metals market. And when an influx of new technical buyers all enter at once -- a surge in price is going to result. The bears are therefore defending this exact technical level we are monitoring. The tightness of the battle is now evident down to the intraday level, where we have observed sellers appearing above $1,355 per ounce and buyers appearing in the $1,330 region over the last week.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-664" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/b_Gold-1year-forecast.png" alt="Gold-1year-forecast" width="1240" height="928" />

What the tightness of this consolidation means is that the market is nearing a resolution. Typically the break of a significant long-term trend line in gold will result in a quick $50 - $100 movement in price. Following that initial break, a retracement toward the trend line will generally occur. The degree to which gold fully or only partially comes back to retest its broken trend line will give us clues as to the strength of the subsequent advance.

Of course, let us not get ahead of ourselves: the technical breakout has not yet occurred. For the week, gold finished higher marginally by $3.00 to close at $1,346.20, for a modest 0.2% gain from a week prior.

<strong>Seasonal Indian Demand Ahead</strong>

Despite the continued consolidation, sellers will have to be quite determined if they are to continue holding back the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">price of gold</a> once demand begins to emerge within the next month from India. It is during this late August through September period when increased physical demand is seen year after year prior to the Indian wedding season, which begins in October.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-665" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c-gold-demand-country.png" alt="gold-demand-country" width="764" height="726" />

Let us not overlook: Indian demand is critically significant in the physical market. As shown above, India consumes more gold per year than any other country outside China, and more than the United States and Europe combined. And the majority of this demand occurs in the period prior to the October wedding season.

As precious metals investors, we are thus biding our time in waiting mode to monitor the strength of the coming seasonal demand.

&nbsp;

<strong>Silver Update</strong><strong> </strong>

Silver is currently within a midpoint consolidation pattern, with well-defined resistance appearing on the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/silver-price">charts</a> between $20.60 - $20.70. Minor support has appeared over the last seven weeks near $19.20; however, stronger long-term support appears between the $17.50 - $18.50 price zone.

Silver's consolidation is part of a series of imbedded patterns which have appeared since the bottom was confirmed in December 2015 at $13.65 per ounce.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-666" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d-Silver-2013-16.png" alt="Silver-2013-16" width="1240" height="1119" />

Silver's actual bottom took the shape of a bottoming wedge formation, shown in the chart above in turquoise color, indicating broken trend lines. The bottoming wedge is a pattern in which both highs and lows are falling, yet highs are falling at a steeper rate than the subsequent lows. This pattern indicates that buyers are stepping in at relatively higher levels on each decline. The pattern tends to represent a terminal bottom formation, in which buyers eventually overcome sellers and a trend reversal is seen. Silver broke out of the formation in February 2016 and confirmed the December bottom, shown by the red highlight circle above.<strong> </strong>

Remember that these formations merely show us the levels at which large buyers and sellers are entering the market, and the patterns which are defining their behavior. If we study the behavior of large investors and align ourselves with them, we stand to time our entry and exit points better and to potentially achieve a greater profit.

Since the bottom, silver has formed a series of imbedded head and shoulder patterns, the first level of which took place below $16.00, shown in royal blue above.

After breaking higher from $16.00 in April, this pattern targeted $18.25, which was hit in June.

Since achieving its level 1 target, silver now finds itself in the midst of a second-level head and shoulders pattern, which is shown above in the magenta color. The price target for this pattern is between $21.50 - $23.00, and this target is yet to be achieved. $21.50 - $23.00 thus remains our open target for silver's next advance.

Note that silver has a tendency to overshoot technical patterns, as it is a small market and is prone to extreme swings in either direction. We thus maintain the possibility that <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver">silver</a> may overshoot its next target and reach $25 within the next several months, which is an area of strong resistance dating back to 2012.

It is expected that silver will begin this next advance concurrently to gold's breaking of its long-term downtrend, referenced in the gold analysis above.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Seasonal-Indian-Demand-for-Gold.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d-Silver-2013-16.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c-gold-demand-country.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/b_Gold-1year-forecast.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/a-Gold-2009-present.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|Silver-2013-16|gold-demand-country|Gold-1year-forecast|Gold-2009-present</image_alt_text>
		<tags>gold price|invest in gold|silver price</tags>
		<slug>gold-silver-price-technical-update</slug>
		<Date>20160822</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>673</id>
		<title><![CDATA[NEW! The 2016 S&W Silver Proof American Liberty Medals now available on Bullion Exchanges!]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;">The US Mint issued, for the first time since 2011, a new bullion medal available in two, S and W, mintmark versions - the 2016 Silver Proof American Liberty Medal. This stunning silver proof medal got quickly sold out during the first 8 minutes from the moment it was placed for sale on the mint’s website on August 23</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">rd</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 2016.</span>

<b>Hurry up! Get your 2016 S&amp;W Silver Proof American Liberty Medals before they become out of stock!</b>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The exceptional 2016 S&amp;W Silver Proof American Liberty Medals showcase a fresh, contemporary design of Liberty, incorporating the ideals of hope and courage. At the same time, the US Mint used its latest manufacturing and digital technology to produce this remarkable bullion product. This fantastic silver proof medal is the symbol of the American proud numismatic heritage and the Nation’s glimmering future because it replicated the praised obverse and reverse design of the $100 American Liberty High Relief Gold Coin, released in 2015.</span>

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-675" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-W-S-Silver-Proof-American-Liberty-Medal.jpg" alt="2016-W-S-Silver-Proof-American-Liberty-Medal" width="900" height="900" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The heads design of the medal was created by Justin Kunz - the talented US Mint Artistic Infusion Program (AIP) designer. It showcases a new representation of Liberty as a modern woman wearing a crown of olive leaves while trustfully holding in her hands the American flag and a lighted torch. This powerful image was sculpted by the remarkable Phebe Hemphill, who delicately engraved her and designer’s initials on the obverse side, along with the inscriptions “Liberty” and “2016”.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">On the reverse side of the medal is depicted the majestic representation of the beloved American Eagle, created by another talented AIP designer - Paul C. Balan. The image was sculpted by Don Everhart II, the US Mint Sculptor-Engraver, and features a gorgeous eagle gripping an olive branch in its talons while rising in flight – the “embodiment of freedom”. Its image is surrounded by the “DE” and “PCB” initials, the “S” or “W” mintmark and the engraving “United States of America”.</span>

<img class="alignnone wp-image-677" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-w-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal.jpg" alt="2016-w-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal" width="900" height="900" /><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-676" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-s-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal.jpg" alt="2016-s-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal" width="900" height="900" />

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/government-mints/us-mint/">US Mint</a> struck this beautiful silver proof medals at the West Point and San Francisco facilities by using the American Silver Eagle blanks made of 1 oz. of .999 fine silver. Unlike the Liberty gold coin issued in 2015, the 40.6 mm silver proof Liberty medal is not legal tender, and it doesn’t carry a denomination. The US Mint set a production limit of only 12,500 medals and a household limit of just 2 medals per household.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">Shipped encapsulated and carefully placed in a delicate blue velvet display mint box, along with a Certificate of Authenticity, the Silver Proof American Liberty Medal is considered a treasured addition for passionate investors and collectors all over the world. Bullion Exchanges offers you both the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-s-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal-w-box-coa">2016-S Silver Proof American Liberty Medal</a> and the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-s-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal-w-box-coa">2016-W Silver Proof American Liberty Medal</a>, as well as NGC PF69 and PF70 Early Releases graded editions. Don’t miss the opportunity to own them – just follow this link for more details.</span>

<b> Add these very low mintage 2016 S&amp;W Silver Proof American Liberty Medals to your impressive collection today!</b>
<hr />
<span style="font-size: medium;">The purpose of this Bullion Exchanges article is purely informative and shall not be considered as an investment recommendation or advice.</span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-W-S-Silver-Proof-American-Liberty-Medal.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-w-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-s-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>2016-w-s-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal|2016-w-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal|2016-s-silver-proof-american-liberty-medal</image_alt_text>
		<tags>american liberty medals|Proof coins|silver coins</tags>
		<slug>2016-sw-silver-proof-american-liberty-medals-now-available</slug>
		<Date>20160823</Date>
		<category>New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>684</id>
		<title>Markets at Crossroads</title>
		<content><![CDATA[Several interrelated markets are simultaneously at important crossroads, so we want to be aware and prepared for the possibilities that may soon materialize. The (northern hemisphere) summer months tend to be the slowest time of the year not just for precious metals, but for many of the capital markets. There is an old saying: “Sell in May and go away.” Certain years this is more useful advice than others, but the point is that we are nearing the end of what has essentially been range-bound action across the precious metals, stock markets, and currency markets since late spring, even with the dramatic events associated with Brexit in June. One way or another, it appears likely that market action is going to start getting more “interesting” after the end of the summer season, which culminates unofficially on the Labor Day holiday in the US next Monday, September 5.

&nbsp;

<strong>US Stock Market</strong>

The US stock market continues to meander higher, defying most recent analysts’ attempts to pinpoint a top. We remain a somewhat detached observer of the action in broad US stocks, as we hold no investments in them directly. However, all markets are somewhat interrelated, and as precious metals and stocks can sometimes be counter-cyclical, we are, by owning precious metals, by default “short” such other markets.

Taking the long-term view of the US Dow Jones Industrial Average, the most likely scenario we see is that the market is forming a generational-timeframe “expanding megaphone” top. The expanding megaphone is a topping pattern with several successive highs and successive lows, each high being above the previous high, and each low being below the previous low. It takes the shape of an expanding outward cone or megaphone. The pattern shows a bifurcated market experiencing extreme swings in psychology every several years, a scenario which usually does not end with a positive resolution.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-685" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/a-stocks-dow-1980-present.png" alt="stocks-dow -1980-present" width="1240" height="928" />

We have had three hits along the upper trend line of this pattern since the year 2000, and two hits on the lower trend. Consequently, the pattern calls for a drop in the Dow down to the lower trend line at minimum, for a third hit, at some point over the next 3-5 years. Based on the projection, this would equate roughly Dow 5,000.

Long-term patterns such as this are certainly not appropriate for immediate trading, and indeed as we have seen potential tops can take much longer to materialize than most anticipate. It is quite possible for the stock market to continue grinding higher for another year or two as part of this formation.

However, the level of complacency seen in the market now is certainly at levels ripe for a top to form. Most employees are blissfully happy to continue contributing to stock 401(k) retirement funds, secure in the knowledge of slow and steady annual gains.

History shows that such psychological complacency is typically a precursor to significant market corrections.

&nbsp;

<strong>US Bond Market</strong>

In generations past, bonds and stocks were considered opposite ends of the investment spectrum. Stocks were seen as vehicles for growth and appreciation, and bonds were seen as investments for safety. As such, during times when stocks fell, funds often moved into bonds. And during times when stocks were appreciating, money conversely moved out of bonds.

With the advent of unprecedented money-printing by the Fed after the 2008 financial crisis, all of that changed. For the first time in the modern era, since 2008 we have seen both stock and bonds rising in near unison. Keep in mind the above graph of the Dow – which is at an all-time high -- when we look at the following graph of US 30-year bond prices over the same time period:

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-686" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/b-us-bonds-1980-present.png" alt="us-bonds-1980-present" width="1240" height="737" />

As we can see, US 30-year bond prices are also at all-time highs, which is what has forced their yields to all-time lows.

This is the first occasion in modern US history when both stock and bond prices are simultaneously at all-time highs. When we say we are living through an unprecedented time, we mean it literally.

How is it possible that so much money is flowing both into stocks (growth assets) and bonds (safety assets) at the same time?

The answer is simple. The Fed has printed so much money over the last eight years, that it is searching for a home somewhere… anywhere. Fundamentals have been pushed aside, and money is flowing wherever it can in search of some type of return.

The Fed has turned on a fire hose in an attempt to fill a bathtub. While the tub is certainly getting filled, so is the rest of the bathroom, the living room, and the downstairs apartment, for that matter.

The only question that remains is where is all this money going to flow when these trends reverse, and we see what may be for the first time in history falling stock and bond prices simultaneously?

It is estimated that the size of the global bond market is roughly $100 trillion, while the size of the global equity markets are nearly $70 trillion. Meanwhile, the dollar amount of all the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold </a>ever mined in the history of the world is close to $8 trillion, but less than half of that is available for investment (the rest is held as jewelry and industrial fabrication).

What is setting up when even a small portion of the $170 trillion in combined bond + equity markets attempts to start exiting those assets and to find a home in precious metals will make the moves we have witnessed thus far look like a mere warmup.

Stay tuned… the bubble behavior in bonds and stocks has not culminated yet… but Stein’s Law says: “That which cannot continue forever will one day stop.” And that day is drawing closer.

&nbsp;

<strong>Gold Analysis</strong>

Despite the $20 or 1.5% drop seen in gold this week and the whipsawing that occurred on Friday after Yellen’s comments, the situation in the world’s monetary element remains largely unchanged from a technical standpoint.

On the near-term <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">chart gold</a> is still awaiting a resolution of the convergence of the multiple trend lines we have been monitoring since June. Resistance continues to appear every time gold approaches $1,355 - $1,378, while support is emerging above the $1,285 - $1,306 zone labeled in green. Gold’s primary blue rising channel remains in play until proven otherwise, and one or more of these trends will be forced to break within the next 6 weeks.

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-687" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c-gold-2015-2017-forecast.png" alt="-gold-2015-2017-forecast" width="1240" height="928" />

The action on Friday, although disappointing to watch throughout the day, was not altogether bad from a technical perspective. Below we are zooming the above chart in to the 1-month perspective to analyze the Japanese candlesticks -- each representing one day’s price action:

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-688" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d-candlesticks.png" alt="candlesticks" width="131" height="196" />

The pattern seen on Friday is called a gravestone doji in Japanese candlestick analysis, because it looks like a gravestone with a long upper shadow. Context is critical for evaluation of these candlesticks. When gravestone dojis occur after a strong advance, they can be a sign of a top, as the price rises above a specific price level but then falls back below it later in the day.

Yet when gravestone dojis occur near an area of support, they typically indicate budding strength to come. In this case, we can see a very similar doji that appeared three weeks prior, circled in red. Note that the day represented a local support, after which prices rose over the next week.

Gravestone dojis do not always represent exact bottoms, but they do show us that there are buyers lurking in the background. The pattern should be considered a warning to the bears that they are losing their grip on the recent decline.

If a short-term bottom indeed emerges here after this gravestone doji, we will be looking for another attempt at gold breaking its long-term (magenta) downtrend within the next 1-2 weeks.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/markets.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/d-candlesticks.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/c-gold-2015-2017-forecast.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/b-us-bonds-1980-present.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/a-stocks-dow-1980-present.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>markets-at-crossroad-gold|candlesticks|-gold-2015-2017-forecast|us-bonds-1980-present|stocks-dow -1980-present</image_alt_text>
		<tags>Gold Analysis|gold forecast|gold price</tags>
		<slug>markets-crossroads</slug>
		<Date>20160829</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>693</id>
		<title>The US Mint releases the 2016 Standing Liberty Quarter Centennial Gold Coin on 8th of September</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;">The second highly anticipated coin of the current year - the 2016 Standing Liberty Quarter Centennial Gold Coin - will be soon released by the US Mint. This stunning coin, celebrating 100 years of mintage, will be placed for sale on September 8, 2016, at 12 noon Eastern Time. This breathtaking rendition of an iconic 1916 design is expected to sell out in less than an hour, just like the previous coin in the anniversary series - the 2016 Mercury Dime Centennial Gold Coin.</span>

<b>Order your</b><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-1-4-oz-standing-liberty-centennial-gold-coin-100th-anniversary-w-box-coa"> <b>2016 Standing Liberty Quarter Centennial Gold Coin</b></a><b>!</b>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-700" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold-coin.jpg" alt="2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold--coin" width="750" height="750" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The US mint centenary anniversary series includes renditions of the three most beloved numismatic coins of 1916:</span>
<ul>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 2016 Mercury Dime Centennial Gold Coin, released in April 2016</span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">2016 Standing Liberty Quarter Centennial Gold Coin</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, offered on September 8, 2016</span></li>
 	<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 2016 Walking Liberty Half Dollar Centennial Gold Coin – TBD.</span></li>
</ul>
<span style="font-weight: 400;">These long-awaited gold coins are highly sought-after by collectors all over the world due to the tremendous popularity of the original circulating coins.</span>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-701" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-standing-liberty-quarter-gold-coin.jpg" alt="2016-standing-liberty-quarter-gold--coin" width="750" height="750" />

&nbsp;

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The 2016 Standing Liberty Quarter <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold/us-gold-coins/us-commemorative-coins/2016-centennial">Centennial Gold Coin</a> features the original Bare Breasted “Standing Liberty” depiction, designed by the talented sculptor Hermon A. MacNeil and used for the circulating coin in 1916. However, the image was changed for the 1917-1930 coin issues, having Liberty covered with a chainmail either as a World War I symbol or because of multiple complaints regarding her nudity.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">On the obverse side of this splendid gold coin is engraved the image of Liberty holding a shield in her left hand and an olive branch in her right hand while stepping through a wall opening which contains the 13 five-pointed stars – the symbol of the Original Thirteen Colonies. This outstanding representation also contains the engravings “Liberty”, “In God We Trust”, “2016”, “AU 24K”, “1/4 oz”, “W” mintmark and the designer’s initial “M”. The reverse side of this beautiful centennial coin showcases a majestic eagle with its wings outstretched, flanked by the 13 stars, seven on the left and six on the right, and encircled by the inscriptions “Quarter Dollar”, “E Pluribus Unum” and “United States of America”.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">This spectacular coin was struck at the West Point facility from 1/4 troy ounces of .9999 pure gold, the size being the symbol of the coin’s face value. It was produced with reeded edges and business strike finish, with a limited mintage of 100,000 bullion coins and a limited household order of just one coin. The US Mint will provide each coin encapsulated and delicately hand-packaged in an elegant custom-designed black matte hardwood presentation box, accompanied by a Certificate of Authenticity.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">As the first centennial coin, the Mercury Dime Gold Coin which went off-sale in less than an hour, the new 2016 Standing Liberty Quarter Centennial Gold Coin is expected to become a treasured keepsake for numismatists and a must-have for any collector.</span>

<b> The</b> <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/catalogsearch/result/index/?cat=0&amp;in_stock_only=0&amp;q=standing+liberty+gold"><b>2016 Standing Liberty Quarter Centennial Gold Coin</b></a><b> – Don’t miss the 2</b><b>nd</b><b> release in the 100</b><b>th</b><b>-anniversary series!</b>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-702" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold-coin-box.jpg" alt="2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold-coin-box" width="750" height="750" />

<span style="font-size: medium;">The purpose of this Bullion Exchanges article is purely informative and shall not be considered as an investment recommendation or advice.</span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold-coin-box.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-standing-liberty-quarter-gold-coin.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold-coin.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-Standing-Liberty-Gold-Coin.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold-coin-box|2016-standing-liberty-quarter-gold--coin|2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold--coin|2016-standing-liberty-gold-coin</image_alt_text>
		<tags>Centennial Coin|Gold Coin|Standing Liberty</tags>
		<slug>us-mint-releases-2016-standing-liberty-quarter-centennial-gold-coin</slug>
		<Date>20160831</Date>
		<category>New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>707</id>
		<title>G20 Meeting to Start a Busy Month in Currency Markets</title>
		<content><![CDATA[Yesterday, Monday, September 5 is Labor Day here in the United States. As such, US markets were closed. Trading has occurred in <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver">silver</a> on other world exchanges... yet as the volume of contracts traded is still mostly dominated by the New York COMEX, we were hesitant to expect any significant moves until Tuesday.

We recently reviewed the first-half 2016 statistics for gold. The international store of wealth had its best first-half in over 30 years -- on a percentage basis up 26%. It is easy to overlook that statistic amidst the consolidation we have seen since June.

Yet that number is telling us something. Tensions must be brewing in the world financial system for gold to rise so significantly in such a short time. For the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">price</a> to rise $300 in six months, large entities were purchasing hundreds of tonnes of metal for weeks on end. We cannot be certain for what reasons they were acting -- those reasons will reveal themselves in time -- but there are four important events coming up over the next 6 weeks that could all have significant impacts on the currency and precious metals markets. They are:

<strong>September 5</strong> - the G20 countries conclude their meeting in Hangzhou, China.

<strong>September 21</strong> - the US Federal Reserve releases its decision on interest rates.

<strong>September 30</strong> - the Chinese yuan is formally included in the SDR reserve system. (The SDR or Special Drawing Right is an International Monetary Fund (IMF) basket of currencies that is increasingly being used instead of the US dollar for loans or aid to recipient nations.)

<strong>October 7</strong> - the IMF conducts its annual meeting in Washington, D.C.

One way or another, it appears that the season set to begin on Tuesday will not feature the same range-bound action that we have witnessed for the last 10 weeks. Things are going to get more volatile, more exciting. We expect these trends to move upward for gold and silver, but if anything changes on that outlook we will be writing about it here.

<u> </u>

<strong><u>US Dollar</u></strong>

On the topic of the currency markets, let us take a look at the action in the US Dollar Index, which measures the dollar against a basket of foreign currencies including the Euro, the Japanese yen, the British pound, the Canadian dollar, the Swedish krona, and the Swiss franc. Despite the surge in the US dollar on the June 24 Brexit vote, the chart of the world’s reserve currency is increasingly looking fragile.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-708" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a-USD-Index.png" alt="USD-Index" width="1240" height="737" />

&nbsp;

The dollar has been consolidating for nearly 20 months. Resistance is well-defined between 99-100 on the Index.  Meanwhile, each successive move into the support zone near 93 has shown technical "cracks". First in August 2015, we note the low in the Dollar Index broke briefly lower to 92, and then in May 2015 the low broke further again to 91.5. These technical cracks in the form of lower lows are alerting us that buyers are not as determined to support the dollar at this juncture as some might assume.

Currently, the dollar finds itself perched precariously just above a short-term support line at 94. A break below 94 and the dollar will be retesting recent lows near 91-92 in short order. Based on the technical weakness observed over the last year, it is likely that if such a retest does occur, it will fail, and the dollar will be heading to new multi-year lows.

This would be positive for the precious metals. While over the long run <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">gold</a> and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/silver-price">silver</a> will be moving higher regardless of the currency denomination, over the short run we should expect to see a more significant move if the US dollar begins to falter.

&nbsp;

<strong><u>Gold Update</u></strong>

Below is the updated 18-month chart for gold. For 10-weeks now gold has been stuck in a consolidation of just 5.5%, between $1,303 and $1,378. Big buyers have bought... big sellers have sold... and now most market participants are waiting -- to see who shows up next. Because after a period of low volatility, the next arrival of a new group of buyers or sellers will determine the market trend for the intermediate future.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-709" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_Gold.png" alt="18-month-chart-gold" width="1240" height="928" />

&nbsp;

The advances seen on Friday in both gold and silver were related to the release of US employment data, which missed analyst estimates. Payrolls were reported at 151,000 additions in August, which was lower than the median forecast of 180,000. The US dollar fell on the news, as the chance of a Federal Reserve rate hike at the upcoming September meeting was dimmed. Conversely, gold and silver both rose.

For the week, gold finished with a nominal gain of $0.80, to close at $1,326 as of the NY COMEX close.

Notably, gold bounced right at the upper region of our green support band shown above, at $1,303 on Thursday.

We continue to watch for a break above the declining magenta-colored long-term downtrend for a signal that the next stage of the bull market will soon begin.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/G20-meeting-currency-markets.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_Gold.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a-USD-Index.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|18-month-chart-gold|USD-Index</image_alt_text>
		<tags>currency markets|gold price</tags>
		<slug>g20-meeting-start-busy-month-currency-markets</slug>
		<Date>20160906</Date>
		<category>Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>719</id>
		<title>Perth Mint will make available its new coin releases starting with September 6, 2016</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<b>Perth Mint will make available its new coin releases starting with September 6, 2016</b>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">Perth Mint, Australia’s most beloved bullion producer, plans to release at the beginning of this autumn several new coins from its most exceptional series: the brand-new Silver Kangaroo Four-Coin Set, the Star Trek Silver Delta Shaped Coin, the Lunar Rooster Gold &amp; Silver Proof Coins, and the White Lion Cub Silver Proof Coin.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">**</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">September will be a huge month with spectacular releases for the Perth Mint, as the prestigious company plans to impress its collectors and numismatists with these fabulous coins:</span>

&nbsp;

<b>The brand-new Silver Kangaroo 4 Silver Proof Coin set</b>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The newest 2016 Australian Kangaroo Silver Proof Coin set that will contain 4 coins struck from .9999 pure silver in proof quality is the first set from Perth Mint containing four different sizes: 1/10  oz., ¼ oz., ½ oz. and a 1 oz. This set will be produced with an issue limit of 3,000 bundles.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">All 4 coins depict the latest 2016 Australian Kangaroo design on their reverse side: the bounding kangaroo which is surrounded by stylized sunlight rays. The image of the unofficial symbol of Australia is encircled by the inscription “Australian Kangaroo”, the ‘P’ mintmark, “2016” and the weight and purity of the coin.</span>

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-725" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Silver-Kangaroo-4-Silver-Proof-Coin-set-with-p-mintmark.jpg" alt="Silver-Kangaroo-4-Silver-Proof-Coin-set" width="840" height="500" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Perth Mint offers this gorgeous set in a classic presentation case with a customized shipper and a numbered Certificate of Authenticity. The 4-coin set is simultaneously released with the ¼ oz. Silver Kangaroo Proof coin, which is provided in an individual packaging with a limited issue of 10,000 coins.</span>

&nbsp;

<b>Star Trek Delta shaped silver coin – celebrating 50 years of Star Trek</b>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">This one-of-a-kind release from Perth Mint is an exceptional gift option for Star Trek fans. This 1 oz. .999 pure silver coin will have the shape of the Delta Shield from the famous Star Trek science fiction series produced by Gene Roddenberry, which debuted in 1966 and ran until 1969.</span>

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-726" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Star-Trek-Delta-shaped-silver-coin.jpg" alt="Star-Trek-Delta-shaped-silver-coin" width="840" height="500" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Delta Shield shaped coin will feature the 50</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Anniversary Delta Shield logo on its reverse side. The coin will be issued as a Tuvalu legal tender coin, offered in a contemporary acrylic display case, and will be accompanied by a numbered Certificate of Authenticity. The Perth Mint will produce no more than 5,000 of these outstanding coins celebrating the Star Trek 50</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> anniversary – a true must-have for any Star Trek fan or collector!</span>

&nbsp;

<b>The 2017 Lunar Rooster Gold &amp; Silver Proof &amp; Bullion coins</b>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The internationally renowned Australian </span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold/australian-gold-coins/perth-mint-gold-lunar"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gold </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver/coins/australian-silver-coins/silver-lunar-coins"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Silver </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lunar Series II will be completed with the 2017 proof and bullion issues that celebrate the Year of the Rooster – the 10</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> animal in the Chinese Zodiac Calendar. The birth dates for the ‘Year of the Rooster’ are 1921, 1933, 1945, 1957, 1969, 1981, 1993, 2005, and 2017. The people born under this sign are considered as hardworking, honest, loyal, and sociable. These famous Lunar Series coins will be struck from .9999 pure gold and .9999 pure silver in proof and bullion quality.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Lunar Rooster Proof Gold Coins will be available in three sizes, 1 oz., ¼ oz. and 1/10 oz., as well as in a three-coin set. These remarkable coins will have a limited issue: no more than 3,000 1oz. coins, 5,000 ¼ coins, 4,000 1/10 oz. coins and 1,500 three-coin sets. The bullion edition will have an unlimited issue of 1/20 oz., 1/10 oz., ¼ oz., ½ oz., 2 oz., 10 oz. and 1 kg gold coins and a maximum of 30,000 1 oz. coins which are expected to be highly collectable. Both proof and bullions coins will depict on their reverse side the new ‘Year of the Rooster’ design: a rooster standing in front of a stylized Chinese scene with bamboo and leaves, encircled by the inscription ‘Year of the Rooster’, the Chinese character for ‘rooster’ and the ‘P’ mintmark.</span>

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-727" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/The-2017-Lunar-Rooster-Gold-Silver-Proof-Bullion-coins.jpg" alt="2017-Lunar-Rooster-Gold-Silver-Proof-Bullion-coins" width="842" height="431" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The Lunar Rooster Proof Silver Coins are also available in three sizes, 1 kilo, 1 oz. and ½ oz. and the three-coin set. These fantastic coins will have a limited issue of 500 1 kilo coins, 5,000 1 oz. coins, 8,000 ½ oz. coins, and 1,000 three-coin sets. The bullion versions will have an unlimited issue of 1 kg, 10 oz., 5 oz., 2 oz., and ½ oz. coins and a maximum of 100 10 kg. and 300,000 1 oz. silver coins. Just like the gold edition, the 1 oz. silver bullion “The Year of Rooster” coin is expected to sell out quickly. Both proof and bullion silver coins feature on their reverse side the new ‘Year of the Rooster’ design: the rooster, hen and the three chicks standing amongst flowers and bamboo, surrounded by the ‘P’ mintmark, the engraving ‘Year of the Rooster’ and the Chinese character for ‘rooster’.</span>

&nbsp;

<b>4</b><b>th</b><b> issue in the adorable Cubs series – </b><span style="line-height: 1.75;">This year’s latest Perth Mint release - the Cub series - will be completed with the fourth coin - the September Cubs - which features the playful white lion cubs from South Africa, Timbavati region. This impressive coin will be struck as a Tuvalu legal tender coin, made from ½ oz. of .999 fine silver with a limited mintage of 5,000 coins, depicting the cute white lion design.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The white lion’s color of the coat is white, almost blonde color, which is much lighter than the usual tawny African lion. These lion species are in fact the same, but their white coat is the result of a recessive gene that is carried by both parents which can give birth to both tawny and white cubs. The previous coins depicted the tiger, jaguar and snow leopard cubs and the lynx cub will be depicted on the last, fifth coin in the series.</span>

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-728" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/White-Lion-Cubs-2016-½-Silver-Proof-Coin.jpg" alt="White-Lion-Cubs-2016-1-2-Silver-Proof-Coin" width="840" height="500" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">On the reverse side of this amazing coin are depicted two colored white lion cubs that are playing in the savannah’s grass, surrounded by the word “CUBS” and the ‘P’ mintmark. Besides the classic Perth Mint presentation case, the mint also provides a special display box which can be completed with all five coins that will protect and present them in a superb way.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">**</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">On the obverse side of each of these coins is engraved the effigy of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II, designed by Ian Rank-Broadley, along with the coin’s face value, weight and purity marks. The Star Trek Delta Shaped Silver coin and 2016 White Lion Cubs ½ Silver Proof Coin also contain the “Tuvalu” inscription, while the obverse side of the other coins contains the “Australia” engraving.</span>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PqyMCmYZT1g" width="840" height="472.5" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>

&nbsp;

<b>About Perth Mint</b>

<b>Perth Mint</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is the most prestigious Australian Mint, which was established in 1899 by the Royal Mint. The British Mint opened its branch after Britons discovered vast gold deposits in Australia. Today, this premium refinery is accredited by COMEX, DMCC, TOCOM and LBMA, being famous for producing splendid bullion items such as:</span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold/bars/perth-mint-gold-bars"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">gold bars</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, coins, and</span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver/coins/australian-silver-coins"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">silver coins</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, including the </span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold/australian-gold-coins/perth-mint-gold-lunar"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lunar</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold/australian-gold-coins/perth-mint-kangaroo"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kangaroo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> series. The mint is also famous for creating the finest gold plate made of 13 troy ounces of .999999 pure gold in 1957, which was used as a benchmark by the Royal Mint.</span>

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/perth-mint-september-releases.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/White-Lion-Cubs-2016-½-Silver-Proof-Coin.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/The-2017-Lunar-Rooster-Gold-Silver-Proof-Bullion-coins.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Star-Trek-Delta-shaped-silver-coin.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Silver-Kangaroo-4-Silver-Proof-Coin-set-with-p-mintmark.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2017-1-oz-Silver-Lunar-Year-of-The-Rooster-BU-Australian-Perth-Mint-In-Capsule.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>perth-mint-september-releases||2017-Lunar-Rooster-Gold-Silver-Proof-Bullion-coins||Silver-Kangaroo-4-Silver-Proof-Coin-set|2017-1-oz-Silver-Lunar-Year-of-The-Rooster-BU-Australian-Perth-Mint</image_alt_text>
		<tags>Lunar Coin|Perth Mint</tags>
		<slug>perth-mint-new-coin-releases-september-6</slug>
		<Date>20160909</Date>
		<category>Market News|New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>732</id>
		<title>Bond Jitters and Precious Metals Updates</title>
		<content><![CDATA[Coming into September, and especially with the drop in stocks on Friday, there is a lot of fear about what will happen over the next few weeks in the markets.

There seems to be a general sense of unease that develops during September and October, likely due to the high confluence of market crashes that have occurred during this time. The stock market crash of 1929 began in October of that year. The crash of 1987 occurred in October as well. And the financial crisis of 2008 intensified rapidly during September and October.

Perhaps there is something ingrained in our seasonal cycle as human beings that leads us to grow cautious as the days become shorter and the temperatures get colder (in the northern hemisphere)... and somehow this innate worry translates into a high correlation with stock market panics over the last 100 years.

Friday saw a strong down day in US stocks, as it appears the summer lull has ended for the markets. The S&amp;P 500 Index of US companies fell nearly 2.4% for the day, the largest percentage drop since the day of the Brexit vote in June.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-733" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a_Friday-SP-500-Index-US-companies.png" alt="Friday-S&amp;P-500-Index-US-companies" width="1002" height="670" />

&nbsp;

Yet the interesting point is that US 20-year bonds -- which throughout most of history would see safe-haven buying on a strong down day in stocks -- fell on Friday as well. This is most unusual, and merits close monitoring over the months to come, as it is a fundamental component of our long-term thesis for ownership of <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/how-to/gold-vs-silver-vs-platinum-vs-palladium">precious metals</a>. That is: if both stocks and bonds were to fall for the first time in unison over the years to come -- gold would emerge as a final safety asset.

Indeed, although gold was down on Friday by 0.6%, it performed well on a relative basis when compared to bonds, which were down 1.6%.

Relative strength is an indicator we use quite frequently, as it shows certain investors stepping in to buy one asset, even as most other assets are being sold. This is especially important when comparing typical "safety" assets. While one-day of price action is not enough to call this a trend, in prior articles we have discussed why we are on alert for what will eventually be a 35+ year top in long bonds at some point before the close of the decade.

Where will the world turn for safety when US bonds, the asset known to fulfill this role for over a generation, loses its status as such?

A long-term decline in bonds coinciding with a long-term decline in stocks would be something never witnessed in modern history... but all signs indicate that it is exactly the scenario which is now brewing. Of course, bubbles are notorious for taking longer to pop than most people expect -- and thus there still may be one more final "blow-off" phase in US bond prices that perhaps could see yields go fully negative (as they have in other countries). But "the writing is on the wall" for what is coming, and it is going to be a fascinating time not only to be an investor, but generally to be a citizen of this world.

<strong>Gold Update</strong>

Gold saw nothing less than its fourth attempt this week to overcome the long-term resistance that we have been monitoring for the better part of the last three months, the price level for which currently comes in near $1,360. The price spiked up to $1,356 on Monday and Tuesday, and then once again sellers showed up during the remainder of the week to drive the price back down toward $1,330. This consolidation between $1,300 and the downtrend line referenced in the magenta color has been ongoing for 11-weeks now, and it is nearing a resolution.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-734" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_Gold1Y.png" alt="Gold-1year-forecast" width="1240" height="928" />

&nbsp;

The reason we are paying so much attention to the pending break of this long-term trendline is that it is going to represent the shifting in psychology from bear to bull market for the final group of investors who are still clinging to the possibility that gold will be making a new low, below the December 2015 bottom at $1,045.

The price action that we witness after these converging sets of trend lines resolve should not resemble what has happened over the last several months. A stronger trending move should occur, which will result in a new wave of investors becoming interested in the sector.

Although it appears on the chart above that the converging consolidation could last through February 2017, in studying these types of patterns in the past we can say that they generally do not last beyond the 2/3 timeframe mark. The pattern is currently nearing the half-way mark, and we feel a break is imminent at any time now. It would take a drop in gold below the bottom level of the green support zone -- $1,285 -- to make us question the likelihood for the anticipated advance to come this fall.

For now, we continue to see buyers step into the gold market each time the price approaches $1,300.

&nbsp;

<strong>Silver Update</strong>

After making another attempt to overcome the key psychological $20 figure, silver fell back starting on Wednesday and finished flat for the week, closing just above $19.

Of note is the weakness that silver saw on Friday relative to gold, falling 2.8% to gold's 0.6% by the close of the day. This phenomenon is common on days when the stock market is seeing a strong sell-off and gold is falling even modestly. In such instances silver tends to multiply the losses in the two markets, seeing selling both from the precious metals sector and also from the industrial sector.

In a steady stock market with rising <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">gold prices</a>, it is often the case that silver will amplify the gains in <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> as it benefits from both sectors.

This is all part of silver's dual-personality behavior, which makes it one of the most interesting yet volatile commodities in the world. We are now seeing 5% intra-week swings in this precious metal, which will only amplify over the next few years.

With the approach of $20 this week and then backing off again into the mid-range of the consolidation, silver's short-term pattern is increasingly appearing to be a bull-flag correction. Seen often on individual stocks, this pattern generally represents a half-way downward-sloping pause in a primary advance.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-735" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/c_Silver-price-1year.png" alt="Silver-price-1year" width="1240" height="928" />

&nbsp;

In this case, the surge (or "pole" of the flag pole) was from early June at $15.80 through July at $21.25: an amplitude of $5.45.

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver">Silver</a> made a 2-week bottom in mid-August at $18.50, and it is quite possible that this was the low for the bull flag correction.

With an amplitude of $5.45, the pattern would target a <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/silver-price">silver price</a> of $25.45 when added to the breakout point of the flag. Such is in line with our expectations for silver's seasonal advance to come. We will confirm the pattern when the short-term (dashed teal-color) resistance line is broken to the upside.

Our worst-case scenario would be for silver to fall into the lower range of the green support band near $17.50 prior to its next attempt at an advance.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Bond-Jitters-and-Precious-Metals-Updates.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/c_Silver-price-1year.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_Gold1Y.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a_Friday-SP-500-Index-US-companies.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text><![CDATA[Bond-Jitters-Precious-Metals-Updates|Silver-price-1year|Gold-1year-forecast|Friday-S&P-500-Index-US-companies]]></image_alt_text>
		<tags>gold market|gold price|silver price</tags>
		<slug>bond-jitters-precious-metals-updates</slug>
		<Date>20160912</Date>
		<category>Market News|Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>741</id>
		<title>Bullion Exchanges is excited to offer you the special 30th anniversary 2016 1 oz. Proof Silver American Eagle Coin!</title>
		<content><![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;">The one-of-a-kind 2016 anniversary edition of the 1 oz. Proof Silver American Eagle Coin will be released by the US Mint on September 16, 2016, at 12 PM, Eastern Time.</span>

<img class="wp-image-743 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-Anniversary-wBox-COA.jpg" alt="2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-Anniversary" width="800" height="800" />

<b>Get your unique </b><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-w-1-oz-proof-silver-american-eagle-w-box-coa"><b>2016 1 oz. Proof Silver American Eagle Coin</b></a><b> with smooth, lettered edge celebrating 30</b><b>th</b><b> years of minting excellence!</b>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">This year, the </span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/government-mints/us-mint"><span style="font-weight: 400;">US Mint </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">celebrates 30 years since the release of this exceptional coin. The first Proof American Silver Eagles have been produced in 1986. Since their release up until 1992, the coins carried the “S” mintmark of the San Francisco facility. Between 1993 and 2000, the coins displayed the “P” mintmark, being produced at the Philadelphia facility while starting with 2001 (except for 2009 when the US Mint didn’t issue any Proof Silver Eagles) the coins carry the “W” mintmark and are struck at the West Point facility. The splendid 2016 Proof Silver American Eagle Coin consists of one troy ounce of .999 pure silver, has an exceptional mirror-like finish, comes with the $1 face value, and its weight and purity are guaranteed by the US Government.</span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">On the obverse side of the coin is displayed the prize worthy image designed by Adolph A. Weinman, the famous American sculptor-engraver. The image represents the well-known Walking Liberty design which was previously struck on the Walking Liberty Half Dollars and features the Lady Liberty holding laurel and oak branches in her left hand while moving confidently towards the sunlight - the symbol of our Nation’s strength. The graceful full-length figure of Liberty is enveloped in the US Flag’s folds and surrounded by the inscriptions “Liberty”, “In God We Trust”, and “2016”.<img class="aligncenter wp-image-746" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-back.jpg" alt="2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-back" width="800" height="800" /></span>

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The reverse design of the Proof Silver American Eagles was created by the former US Mint Chief Sculptor-Engraver, John M. Mercanti, and showcases the image of the majestic heraldic eagle, holding an olive branch in its right talon, arrows in its left talon, a banner with the words “E Pluribus Unum” in its beak and carrying its shield. This representation is the symbol of the preparedness to defend the United States of America, as well as the desire for peace. The thirteen stars symbolizing the thirteen original colonies are displayed above the eagle’s image, which is encircled by the engravings “One Dollar”, “United States of America” and the weight and purity of the coin.</span>

<img class="aligncenter wp-image-747" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-anniversary.jpg" alt="2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-anniversary-edge" width="800" height="800" />

<span style="font-weight: 400;">The exclusive feature of the stunning 2016 1 oz. Proof Silver American Eagle Coin is the unique smooth edge with the incused “30</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Anniversary” lettering instead of the regular reeded edge. This splendid anniversary edition is offered by the US Mint in an elegant satin-lined, blue velvet presentation box, accompanied by the special 30</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">-anniversary Certificate of Authenticity. Besides having the Proof Silver Eagles in their original packaging, we will also offer you the 30th anniversary coin in Proof 69 (PF69) &amp; Proof 70 (PF70) versions, from both PCGS and NGC, with the designations of Early Release and First Strike, as well as the highly desired First Day of Issue (FDOI) </span><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver/coins/us-silver-coins/certified-silver-eagles"><span style="font-weight: 400;">certified coins</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span>

<b>Order this outstanding </b><a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/2016-w-1-oz-proof-silver-american-eagle-w-box-coa"><b>2016 1 oz. Proof Silver American Eagle Coin</b></a><b>– 30</b><b>th</b><b>-anniversary edition today!</b>

&nbsp;]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-anniversary.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-back.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-Anniversary-wBox-COA.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-anniversary-edge|2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-back|2016-W-1-oz-Proof-Silver-American-Eagle-30th-Anniversary</image_alt_text>
		<tags>Silver Eagle</tags>
		<slug>30th-anniversary-2016-1-oz-proof-silver-american-eagle-coin</slug>
		<Date>20160913</Date>
		<category>Miscellaneous|New Releases</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>752</id>
		<title>Rising Interest Rates Correspond with Rising Gold Prices</title>
		<content><![CDATA[Gold's summer consolidation stretches on for another week, and this time tests the lower boundary of the support zone labeled below, closing at $1,310. For the week, the international currency of last resort closed down by $24 or some 1.8%.

This was the 4th distinct hit on the green support zone since June, which closely matches the number of attempts gold has made to overcome the long-term downtrend shown below in magenta. All eyes now turn to the US Federal Reserve policy meeting on Wednesday as the next likely catalyst to kick gold out of this consolidation in one way or another.

<img class="size-full wp-image-753 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a_Gold.png" alt="a_Gold-FED-polycy" width="1240" height="928" />

On the subject of the coming Fed meeting, there is a continuous falsehood portrayed in the mainstream media regarding the effects of rising interest rates on the prices of precious metals. Another one of these misleading articles was published this week in Bloomberg.

&nbsp;

<strong>The falsehood is that rising interest rates are negative for precious metals.</strong>

The theory is that rising interest rates increase the attractiveness of interest-bearing accounts, such as US dollar-denominated bonds or savings accounts. This, in turn, should cause investors to turn away from gold, as it pays no interest.

The mainstream media will publish articles explaining this theory every few months, typically when gold has been weak in price, as a way to explain the recent trading action. Here is a snippet of the recent article from Bloomberg and the highlighted section reveals the erroneous statement: <em>"Gold would get hit pretty hard in a rising rate environment."</em>

<em><img class="size-full wp-image-754 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_Article-Bloomberg-Gold.png" alt="Article-Bloomberg -Gold" width="643" height="898" /></em>

Yet the actual data for rising interest rates and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">precious metals prices</a> is completely contrary to this statement. All we need to do is examine the history of rising interest rate cycles and gold prices, and the correlation is plain to see.

&nbsp;

<strong>Interest Rates and Precious Metals Prices</strong>

Let us give two examples to illustrate the true correlation between short-term interest rates and precious metals prices.

First, the example from the most recent multi-year rate hike cycle. Below is a chart of the 2003 - 2007 time period, showing short-term interest rates rising from 1% to 5.25%. Following that is a <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">chart of gold prices</a> over the same time period.

&nbsp;

<img class="size-full wp-image-757 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/C_Fed_20032007.jpg" alt="Fed-20032007" width="798" height="357" />

<img class="size-full wp-image-758 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/D_Gold_2003-2007.jpg" alt="Gold-Price-2003-2007" width="886" height="578" />

Here, we can clearly see that a rise in interest rates corresponded to a rise in gold prices, as the price of the metal rose from $325 to over $800 during this same time period.

Now let us look at a longer-term example, the multi-decade rise in interest rates from 1955 - 1980.

<img class="size-full wp-image-759 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/E_Fed-Funds-rate-1955-1980.jpg" alt="Fed-Funds-rate-1955-1980" width="645" height="359" />

<img class="size-full wp-image-760 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/F_Gold-1955-1980.jpg" alt="Gold-1955-1980" width="876" height="579" />

To be as concise as possible: a rising interest rate environment over these 25 years was the backdrop to the largest precious metals bull market in modern history, as gold broke the dollar standard at $35 per ounce and advanced over 2,000% through 1980.

&nbsp;

<strong>Why do precious metals rise with rising interest rates?</strong>

In order for this to make sense, we must alter our perspective of the Federal Reserve from what is discussed in the news. <strong>The Fed is a reactive, not a proactive organization.</strong> The Fed responds to incoming data related to prices, employment, and the solvency of its own member banks -- and then responds with monetary policy after the fact.

The Fed has no crystal ball. Being reactive, when would the Fed logically decide to raise interest rates? Only when it is forced to do so. In other words, the Fed raises interest rates only when the inflationary effects of its previous money-printing cycle are starting to be obvious in the broader economy.

<a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">Gold </a>is the ultimate protection from inflation, and this is why it tends to rise in a rising interest rate environment. Like a well-trained hound, gold sniffs out looming inflation better than any data possibly could.

It is uncertain why the mainstream media continues to purport this false idea regarding rising interest rates and precious metals prices. It may simply be one of those myths that takes on a life of its own, or it may be scare tactics designed to separate investors from their gold at critical junctures. Regardless of the cause, one would think that such prominent news organizations would check their data before publishing these claims.

<strong>So, for the record: when do gold prices fall relative to interest rates?</strong>

A careful look at the correlation between gold bear markets and interest rate cycles over the last 70 years reveals that <em>gold typically declines <u>after the peak</u> of a rate cycle and as rates remain falling or low</em>. Such was the case for the peak and subsequent declines in gold both in 1980 and in 2011.

Current interest rates at 0.25 - 0.50%, having fallen since 2008 in the short-term cycle and since 1980 in the long-term cycle, are nowhere near a peak at this juncture. If anything rates are now forming a long-term low, from which we may see decades of increases into the future.

<img class="size-full wp-image-761 aligncenter" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/G_Fed-Interest-Rate-History.png" alt="Fed-Interest-Rate-History" width="1500" height="579" />

&nbsp;

<strong>One Final Point</strong><strong> </strong>

This long-term perspective does not necessarily mean that gold will rise on the day of a Fed interest rate hike, whether it be this week, or at the next meeting in December. As ironic as it may be, some short-term traders believe the myth they have been taught through these erroneous articles, and so it becomes self-fulfilling as they sell gold on the news of a rate hike.  All the while, long-term investors are accumulating the metal knowing that the inflation from years of money-printing is starting to appear in the system.

Do not be mislead by the mainstream press: the Fed is reactionary. It increases rates when inflation is noticeable -- and history shows gold rises over the course of such cycles.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Rising-Interest-Rates-Correspond-with-Rising-Gold-Prices.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/G_Fed-Interest-Rate-History.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/F_Gold-1955-1980.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/E_Fed-Funds-rate-1955-1980.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/D_Gold_2003-2007.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/C_Fed_20032007.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_Article-Bloomberg-Gold.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a_Gold.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>Rising Interest Rates Correspond with Rising Gold Prices|Fed-Interest-Rate-History|Gold-1955-1980|Fed-Funds-rate-1955-1980|Gold-Price-2003-2007|Fed-20032007|Article-Bloomberg -Gold|a_Gold-FED-polycy</image_alt_text>
		<tags>FED|gold price</tags>
		<slug>rising-interest-rates-correspond-gold-prices</slug>
		<Date>20160919</Date>
		<category>Market News|Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>769</id>
		<title>Fed Hints at Rate Hike in December</title>
		<content><![CDATA[While the Fed this week once <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/2016/09/19/rising-interest-rates-correspond-gold-prices/">again </a>did not raise interest rates, the significant surge in precious metals seen on Wednesday was based on the change in the wording used in the accompanying policy statement. Whereas over the past few meetings the Fed has given little indication that it was considering a second interest rate hike, this time the central bank used the following distinct language: <em>"The case for an increase in the federal funds rate has strengthened."</em>

As investors, we must remember that we are still living in an unprecedented age for low interest rates. At the 0.25% - 0.50% target rate, this is still the lowest that interest rates have been in the history of the Federal Reserve, including the following two critical time periods:
<ul>
 	<li>The Great Depression: rates hit a low of 1.5%</li>
 	<li>World War II: rates hit a low of 1.0%</li>
</ul>
Can we imagine that what is happening in the world economy currently must be deemed by the Federal Reserve to be more severe than both the Great Depression and the largest international conflict in the history of planet Earth?

Not only are rates lower than in each of these periods, but they have been held lower for a greater number of years than at each of these previous troughs, now eight years and counting below the 1.0% mark. Of course, holding interest rates so low requires a continuous electronic "printing" of new money, which is used to buy the entire short-end of the interbank bond curve. The longer that rates are held below what the market would naturally set them at -- usually between 2.0% - 5.0% -- the more inflation the Fed is building underneath the system.

The data to support this coming wave of inflation can be seen from the graph of the total reserve balances held at the Fed. Recall that what appears on this chart is money the Fed has created in order to buy sufficient bonds needed to force interest rates lower:

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-772" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a_total_reserve_balances_maintained_with_federal_r.jpg" alt="total-reserve-balances-maintained-with-federal-reserve-banks" width="1220" height="556" />

&nbsp;

We can see that there is no precedent for the amount of money created since 2008. The Fed -- and other major world central banks -- have embarked on a money-printing spree that will go down in history as an experiment like none other. Note that there <strong>*is*</strong> a line on this graph dating back to 1950... it is just so low on the Y-axis that it barely registers when compared to the nearly $2.4 trillion created by the bank since 2008.

The strange thing about inflation is that once central banks create it -- they cannot control precisely where it flows after it enters the broad economy. Similar to turning on a fire hose in an attempt to water the garden flowers, some may flow to the intended destination, but far more will eventually flow to unintended areas.

Thus far, the recipients for most of the inflation are clear, and we have discussed them in past articles: world bond and stock markets, which are both at all-time highs simultaneously (in itself an unprecedented situation).

But nothing happens in a vacuum.

Newton's Third Law of Physics says: "For every action there is an opposite and equal reaction." And it appears that the unintended consequence of the Fed's actions are about to be felt elsewhere: in the US dollar.

&nbsp;

<strong><u>US Dollar</u></strong>

The chart below shows the US dollar as measured by the Dollar Index, a trade-weighted basket that measures the value of the US currency versus the sum of the following:
<ul>
 	<li>Euro (EUR), 57.6% weight</li>
 	<li>Japanese yen (JPY) 13.6% weight</li>
 	<li>Pound sterling (GBP), 11.9% weight</li>
 	<li>Canadian dollar (CAD), 9.1% weight</li>
 	<li>Swedish krona (SEK), 4.2% weight</li>
 	<li>Swiss franc (CHF) 3.6% weight</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-773" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_USD-index.png" alt="usd-index" width="1125" height="669" />

&nbsp;

We have been following this chart now for several months, as the dollar has been consolidating for nearly two years between the 92 level and the 100 level on the index.

Over the long run, we expect <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> and <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver">silver</a> to be moving higher in all currencies, no matter what happens with one fiat currency versus another... but over the short run, gold tends to see its most significant advances when the US dollar is weak, as <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">gold is priced</a> primarily in US dollars for purposes of international trade.

Thus, let us remember that the advance seen in gold from the December 2015 low of $1,045 per ounce to the recent high of $1,378 has taken place within a backdrop of a relatively stable US dollar, which has only fallen from 100 to 95 on the Index.

It appears that gold is now waiting for further signals from the currency market in order to begin its next move, and as the dollar has continued to consolidate, so has gold.

Yet these consolidations will not continue forever.

&nbsp;

<strong>Recent Technical Analysis on the Dollar</strong>

On the chart above, we can see converging sets of trendlines, shown in royal blue for primary downward trend and teal for short-term uptrend. These trends have been converging since December 2015 and May 2016, respectively. One of these trends is due to break within the next 4-8 weeks.

While consolidations such as this are inherently neutral when viewed in isolation (they can break either upward or downward), when we view the action within the context of the preceding advance the nearly two-year consolidation in the dollar is increasingly taking the form of a broad long-term top. Indeed, it would be rare to see such a lengthy pattern result in a continuation move higher.

From the short-term perspective, our "hints" that the break will be lower come from the two cracks in the support zone below 93 on the index. These cracks have been warning signs that buyers of the dollar are not as resolute in supporting the currency as many would believe. This is in contrast to the resistance zone at 100, which has shown very distinct and unhesitant selling pressure each time that level is reached.

Should the lower converging (teal color) trendline break in the dollar in the coming weeks, the currency should be making new lows below the 92 region in short order. This move is expected to coincide with the converse breaking of the long-term downtrend that has held the price of gold lower from 2011 - present (see Gold Analysis, below).

&nbsp;

<strong><u>Gold Analysis</u></strong>

Gold made another attempt to overcome its long-term downtrend this week, reaching $1,343 on Thursday before falling back to $1,337 by the end of the week.

This was the fifth attempt by gold to break higher from the current consolidation. Each attempt represents another opportunity as buyers chip away at the overhang of sellers. Although we cannot be certain exactly when the line is going to be crossed, a breakout of this magnitude will leave no doubts when it does occur.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-774" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/c_Gold-price-2015-2016.png" alt="gold-price-2015-2016" width="959" height="718" />

&nbsp;

Resistance is clearly defined by the downtrend as between $1,355 - $1,378.

The rising blue trend channel since the December lows is now coming into focus for support near $1,310, and immediately below that the support zone that has held since June comes in between $1,285 - $1,305.

Longer-term, we must remember that the bottom seen last December was nothing less than a retest of a multi-decade breakout from the 1980 - 2009 consolidation in gold. The move seen from 2009 - 2011 was the initial surge from the breakout. However, multi-decade breakouts do not tend to see their advances finish in two years only. A more significant advance is believed to be in the early stages of developing.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-775" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/d_Gold-1980-present.png" alt="gold-1980-present" width="1125" height="496" />

&nbsp;

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Fed-Hints-at-Rate-Hike-in-December.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/d_Gold-1980-present.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/c_Gold-price-2015-2016.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/b_USD-index.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/a_total_reserve_balances_maintained_with_federal_r.jpg</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>fed-hints-at-rate-hike-in-december|gold-1980-present|gold-price-2015-2016|usd-index|total-reserve-balances-maintained-with-federal-reserve-banks</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>fed-hints-rate-hike-december</slug>
		<Date>20160926</Date>
		<category>Market News|Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>782</id>
		<title><![CDATA[Gold Tests Important Trend & Dow / Gold Ratio Update]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[Since the December 2015 bottom in precious metals, gold has risen $272 or 26% from the low of $1,045 per ounce, to close at $1,317 last Friday. From a technical observation, gold is now directly meeting with its rising linear trendline from the absolute lows (shown in blue). This line acted as support to mark the end of the correction in early June. Of course, the line simply represents big buyers who have been showing up in the gold market at increasingly higher levels over the last six months -- and we now want to see if they will show up again this week, just above $1,300.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-783" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/a_Gold-price-2015-2016.png" alt="gold-price-2015-2016" width="1240" height="928" />

&nbsp;

It will be an important test for gold. If the trend channel from the lows is going to hold, it will exert itself within the next 2-3 days, and the price should fail to close below the line for more than one day. This would then set up gold to attempt to break its long-term downtrend (magenta color) by mid-October.

Should the trendline fail -- it will constitute a technical breakdown in the short-term, but all hope will not be lost for the intermediate outlook . The support zone in the region of $1,306 -- which extends down to $1,285 and is shown in green -- has held <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> higher on four separate occasions over the last three months, and it is expected to continue to do so should the linear trend no longer remain in tact.

As investors in the volatile metals, we must expect the prices to move in a series of surges, consolidations, and corrections over the course of the next several years.

Nearing the bottom of the most recent trading range, the mood in the precious metals community has turned decidedly negative in the short-run, despite what has been less than a 5% correction in the <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">gold price</a> since late-June. Recent headlines from Bloomberg this week include "Bulls Feeling Frayed as Gold's First-Half Run Fades Into History" and "Gold-Mining Investors hit by the Hitters as Share Rally Sputters".

It is said that corrections can manifest either in price or in time -- and in this case it is clearly happening in the later. Yet no matter which form they take, both price and time corrections serve to set the stage for the next round of advances as weak hands get flushed out of the market and new investors arrive.

When viewing mainstream articles that focus mostly on sentiment, it is helpful to remember that sentiment must necessarily be worst in the terminal stages of a correction, as quotes and headlines come from those who have already sold. And when a critical majority has sold, this is when a bottom in price is imminent.
<h2>Dow / Gold Ratio Update</h2>
The <strong>Dow to Gold ratio</strong> provides an excellent way to view the long-term real value potential for gold relative to the broad US stock market.

As discussed in past articles, the ratio has approached a 1:1 reading twice prior in the last century at precious metals peaks: in 1932 when the Dow crashed to the low 40's and gold was revalued from $20 to $35 per ounce, and again in 1980 when the Dow sat at 850 and gold exceeded $850 per ounce.

We expect that the ratio will hit 1:1 again before this cycle is completed in favor of precious metals.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-784" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/b_Dow-Gold-ratio-long-term.png" alt="dow-gold-ratio-long-term" width="1340" height="737" />

&nbsp;

Updating the analysis, with the Dow at 18,308 as of Friday, September 30 and gold at $1,314 per ounce, the ratio stands at 13.9 : 1. The 1:1 target could thus occur with stocks staying flat and gold approaching $18,000 per ounce, or the Dow falling to 2,500 and gold rising to meet it at $2,500 per ounce. Either way, the result should be over a 90% loss in value in real terms for US stocks before the next precious metals peak occurs.

Although such gains for gold or drops in the Dow may seem extreme given current prices, imagine that the same must have been felt with gold at $35 per ounce and the Dow at 900 in 1968. Yet the two did meet 12 years later.

Presently, the Dow / Gold ratio is in the later stages of a counter-cyclical uptrend, shown by the blue line above, amidst the generational downtrend shown in magenta.

Zooming in above on the counter-cyclical uptrend in favor of stocks since 2011, we see that the advance in the ratio has been halted by the declining long-term downtrend, and is now forming an ugly topping pattern, seen as a bearish-slanted head &amp; shoulders formation in the Dow / Gold Ratio:

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-785" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/c_Dow-Gold-ratio-2012-2016.png" alt="dow-gold-ratio-2012-2016" width="1240" height="737" />

&nbsp;

Once the support of the right shoulder is breached, the intermediate downward target for the pattern is measured at 9.0 on the Dow / Gold ratio, which should correspond to either the loss in value in stocks or the surge in price in gold -- both of which will cause increased attention toward precious metals amongst mainstream investors.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Important-Trend-Dow-Gold-Ratio-Update.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/c_Dow-Gold-ratio-2012-2016.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/b_Dow-Gold-ratio-long-term.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/a_Gold-price-2015-2016.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>|dow-gold-ratio-2012-2016|dow-gold-ratio-long-term|gold-price-2015-2016</image_alt_text>
		<tags></tags>
		<slug>important-trend-dow-gold-ratio-update</slug>
		<Date>20161004</Date>
		<category>Miscellaneous|Precious Metals Investing|Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>792</id>
		<title><![CDATA[Gold & Silver Technical Updates]]></title>
		<content><![CDATA[Last week gold broke down through both its rising linear trendline and the $1,285 - $1,305 horizontal support that had been supporting <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/gold-price">prices</a> since the June Brexit vote. By the end of the week gold had closed at $1,257. The importance of these trendlines is apparent as once they were broken to the downside, a cascade of selling was observed in the futures market.

The first point is we must acknowledge the determination of the sellers who showed up each time at the declining long-term (magenta color) downtrend. These long-term trendlines are critical to monitor for exactly the reason that their strength can be so high -- as can be the significance of their eventual breaking.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-794" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/a_Gold-downtrend-2016.png" alt="gold-downtrend-2016" width="1240" height="928" />

&nbsp;

Our best assessment is that the potential for the next low to form will be in the range of $1,200 - $1,251 for gold. Although this is a wide range that is not suitable for short-term trading, there are a confluence of support levels in this region where we place the highest likelihood for a low to now form in gold:
<ul>
 	<li>$,1251 - the 61.8% Fibonacci level of the primary December through July advance.</li>
 	<li>$1,232 - an equal-distance decline of the $$73 amplitude of the June through September consolidation between $1,305 and $1,378.</li>
 	<li>$1,212 - the 50% Fibonacci level of the same advance.</li>
 	<li>$1,200 - horizontal support which held from February through June.</li>
</ul>
When there is a confluence of four technical support levels within such a range, we place a high likelihood for the next intermediate low to form within this price zone.

We should also note that immediately below this support zone is what is labeled "Must Hold Zone" for gold. This region is defined by the 38.2% Fibonacci level of the primary advance at $1,173 and broken October 2015 resistance-turned-support which is appearing near $1,200. This zone represents the lowest possible support for which we could still maintain the thesis that gold is in a new bull market. A break below $1,173 would raise the scenario that gold would form a new low below $1,045 in 2017. We place the probability of this scenario as low at present, but the support region must be mentioned in the course of due diligence.

<strong>Silver Update</strong>

Silver has now come to the lower range of our likely support zone at $17.50, which is also matching the rising linear trendline of the entire advance since the January lows. This further matches closely with the 50% Fibonacci retracement of the advance at $17.42.

The rising linear trendline from the lows has been broken. A recovery of the trend within 1-3 days would constitute a false breakdown in our analysis, but we would need to see <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/charts/silver-price">prices</a> stabilize above $17.95 by Tuesday for this scenario to manifest.

The bullish posture for silver will remain in tact as long as prices remain above the swing low of $15.85 from June. Such would place the current low at higher than the June low, and maintain the series of higher lows that is essential to the early phases of a new bull market.

We do not have a similar "Must Hold Zone" for <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-silver">silver</a> as <a href="http://bullionexchanges.com/buy-gold">gold</a> is seen to be the primary determinant for the precious metals complex at this juncture.

&nbsp;

<img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-795" src="http://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/b_Silver-Must-Hold-Zone-2016.png" alt="silver-must-hold-zone-2016" width="1240" height="928" />

<strong> </strong>

<strong>Chinese Buyers Away Last Week?</strong>

An interesting theory has been circulating that last week's declines in precious metals were purposefully orchestrated to coincide with the ironically-named "Golden Week" period in China. During this semi-annual 7-day holiday, the Chinese financial markets are closed, including the new Shanghai Gold Exchange. As China is still the world's largest consumer of gold, there is merit to the idea that Chinese firms would have withdrawn their bids for physical metal prior to the week, which would have left the market more vulnerable to short sellers.

Ultimately we cannot know the exact extent to which the holiday impacted the losses in the metals last week. We must play the cards we are dealt, and that includes the breakdowns seen over the last several trading days. No matter who did the selling, we want to chart that activity as accurately as possible. My ultimate belief is that any attempts to manipulate markets can only succeed in the short run. The longer a market is suppressed, the more imbalance builds up beneath the system, and like a beach ball held under water, one day it will eventually shoot higher into the air. Throughout history groups have attempted to prop up or suppress one market or another, but they universally fail -- and this time will be no different.

<hr />

<a href="http://iGoldAdvisor.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Christopher Aaron</a>,
Bullion Exchanges Market Analyst

<span style="font-size: medium;">Christopher Aaron has been trading in the commodity and financial markets since the early 2000's. He began his career as an intelligence analyst for the Central Intelligence Agency, where he specialized in the creation and interpretation of pattern-of- life mapping in Afghanistan and Iraq.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">Technical analysis shares many similarities with mapping: both are based on the observations of repeating and imbedded patterns in human nature.</span>

<span style="font-size: medium;">His strategy of blending behavioral and technical analysis has helped him and his clients to identify both long-term market cycles and short-term opportunities for profit.</span>

<span style="font-size: small;"><em>This article is provided as a third party analysis and does not necessarily matches views of Bullion Exchanges and should not be considered as financial advice in any way.</em></span>]]></content>
		<excerpt></excerpt>
		<image_url>https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Gold-and-Siver-Tech-Updates-october.jpg|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/b_Silver-Must-Hold-Zone-2016.png|https://bullionexchanges.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/a_Gold-downtrend-2016.png</image_url>
		<image_alt_text>gold-and-siver-tech-updates-october|silver-must-hold-zone-2016|gold-downtrend-2016</image_alt_text>
		<tags>Gold Analysis|gold trend|silver trend</tags>
		<slug>gold-silver-technical-updates</slug>
		<Date>20161010</Date>
		<category>Miscellaneous|Weekly Market Analysis</category>
	</post>
</data>